<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on MEL.ZHU.ENG</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/</link><description>Recent content in Home on MEL.ZHU.ENG</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Attachment - From Infant to Adulthood</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/blogs/eng/attachment-from-infant-to-adulthood/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/blogs/eng/attachment-from-infant-to-adulthood/</guid><description>Process of Attachment Formation Attachment is a strong, meaningful, emotional bond one forms with another to establish secure bases in this infinite, chaotic, and cold universe. Research have suggested that infants has a biological bias to form such a bond with its primary caregivers (Bowlby, 1969)1. Throughout evolutionary periods, such bias was proven successful for increasing the infant&amp;rsquo;s likelihood to survive. However, in the modern era with time as a scarce resource, child-caring is not the only task for many caregivers, thus many parents has neglected the opportunity to form such bond with its child.</description></item><item><title>Sapien Reflection</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/private/sapien-reflection/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/private/sapien-reflection/</guid><description>Title</description></item><item><title>Studying in psychology</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/private/studying-in-psychology/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/private/studying-in-psychology/</guid><description>How to Study in Psychology The Science of Memory Consolidation Repetition Into Long-Term-Memory My Tools</description></item><item><title/><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/private/%E7%A0%B4%E5%A3%B3%E8%80%8C%E5%87%BA%E7%9A%84%E9%9B%B6%E9%9B%B6%E5%90%8E/00%E5%90%8E%E5%88%B0%E5%BA%95%E6%98%AF%E6%80%8E%E6%A0%B7%E7%9A%84%E4%B8%80%E4%BB%A3%E4%BA%BA/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/private/%E7%A0%B4%E5%A3%B3%E8%80%8C%E5%87%BA%E7%9A%84%E9%9B%B6%E9%9B%B6%E5%90%8E/00%E5%90%8E%E5%88%B0%E5%BA%95%E6%98%AF%E6%80%8E%E6%A0%B7%E7%9A%84%E4%B8%80%E4%BB%A3%E4%BA%BA/</guid><description>在各大社交平台搜索 “00后” 这样的词条，与其关联的结果大多都是些热门的网络现象，例如 ”躺平“，”内卷“，”恐婚恐恋” 等等。而谈论到这些现象，就会发现他们大多都不是正面的，字里行间充斥着失望和担忧。反观00后自己，在这20多岁最好的年华里，他们的的脑海里写满了焦虑，迷茫，几乎没有一点点对于人生的期望。所以，00后们到底怎么了？这些在物质丰富，祖国和平的时代出生的孩子们，为何连活的开心都如此难做到？
00后的标签来自谁 家长的期待 前辈的嫉妒/不解 社会的期待 真实吗 认同吗 不甘吗？ 标签的坏处 局外人的误会 沟通的断层 偏见的反噬 总结：放下标签 开始从头了解00后的成长</description></item><item><title>ANT100: Lecture_1</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/ant100/ant100-lecture_1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/ant100/ant100-lecture_1/</guid><description>Lecture 1 Course overview Privilege is what&amp;rsquo;s not been asked White will not been asks where are they from In the earlier days, most specialist are white men, but most of the groups they studied are people of colour Therefore, according to this tradition, it created a belief there are great differences between different cultures Physical, archaeology, linguist, social-cultural all developed in order as information was passed back from the studies around the world Contemporary anthropology have developed out of the white-male dominated group, and more emphasized were placed on the unique cultures among everyone How the course works Pre-class work (readings)</description></item><item><title>ANT100: Lecture_12</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/ant100/ant100-lecture_12/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/ant100/ant100-lecture_12/</guid><description>Inequality &amp;amp; Post-colony The postcolony ==Postcolony==
A former colony or dominated country, now independent
All former colonies, taken together (roughly: the 3rd world or the Global South)(ex. 台湾)
Inherited means of production from the colonial period, inherited the relations of production
Remaining managers or replaced by local personnel without structural change (integrated)
inequality within and among countries GDP - Gross Domestic Product: a measure of wealth produced in a country or other region ==Unequal development== &amp;ldquo;riches 26 people own more than the poorer 50%&amp;rdquo; Wealthy middle class is expanding in several emerging market countries Raising their GDP statistics, but does not represent the &amp;ldquo;truth&amp;rdquo; The great majority of the very poor continuous to live there Inequalities tend to rise among rich countries Who to blame for the unequal development?</description></item><item><title>ANT100: Lecture_13</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/ant100/ant100-lecture_13/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/ant100/ant100-lecture_13/</guid><description>The Digital Revolution Post-industrial society in the digital age
Human-machine-animal coexistence Purpose of machine: help humans But we fear that this might lead to distraction of human itself (Ai, Robots, Frankenstein) Animal to human transplants Cultural effects of digital technology: Social suite - love, friendship, cooperation, and teaching
Can AI, robots have it? Donna Haraway: Cyborg Manifesto
Arab Spring: Tunisia: Cliams were made that revolutions there happened because of social media</description></item><item><title>ANT100: Lecture_14</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/ant100/ant100-lecture_14/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/ant100/ant100-lecture_14/</guid><description>Intro to Evolutionary Anthropology Reading Anthropology - the global and holistic study of human culture and biology Holistic - considering all aspects of the research subject Morphology(形态学) - the study of the form and structure of organism Ecology - the study of interrelationships of organisms and their environemnt Studies of anthropology Evolutionary Anthology - a discipline within bio-ant, and application of evolutionary theories to study morphology(形态学), ecology(生态), and behaviour of human and non-human primates (primatology), extinct human and non-human primates (paleoanthropology), human diversity and variation, and the various evolutionary factors that influence human health (medical anthropology)</description></item><item><title>ANT100: Lecture_15</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/ant100/ant100-lecture_15/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/ant100/ant100-lecture_15/</guid><description>Intro to Evolutionary Anthropology January 14
Evolutionary Anthropology: Application of modern evolutionary theory to studies of morphology, ecology, and behaviour of human and non-human primates Primatology: Study of non-human primates Paleoanthropology: Study of biological evolution of humans and non-human primates, advent of and changes in human cultural activities, evolutionary of behaviour in humans and non-human primates *Evolution is not about making things better Human Variation: Spatial and temporal variations in human features (such as climatic/geographic variations) Medical Anthropology: How various factors influence health and illness of individuals at small and large levels Forensic Anthropology: Focus on human skeletal remains, seek to determine features of the deceased Scientific Method: S State the problem G Gather information F Form a hypothesis T Test the hypothesis R Record and analyze data S State the conclusion R Repeat the work Multiple scientists do same work, to avoid bias Evolutionary Theory Problems that Limited Evolutionary Theory: Lack of knowledge of age of Earth Religious concept of fixity of species Lack of scientific method Religious notion of separate creation for humans and animals According to Bishop Usher, Earth was created on October 23, 4004 BC (2:30 pm) Fixity of species: All species are unchanging and distinct, as created by God Many ideas and concepts based on verbal accounts of travellers, which were often inaccurate Belief that humans are divine, and above non-human animals Development of Evolution Theory ==Carolus Linneaus== (1707-1778): Father of Taxonomy; grouped species by genus, based on physical resemblances; believed he was classifying God’s creations; Scala Naturae, leading up to humans on top; others continued his work after his death Binomial Nomenclature (system): First letter of genus capitalized, species designation lowercase [ex.</description></item><item><title>ANT100: Lecture_16</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/ant100/ant100-lecture_16/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/ant100/ant100-lecture_16/</guid><description>Principles of Evolution January 28
Genetics Terms Somatic cells - most cells in body, except sex cells Gametes - sex cells Cytoplasm - mix of membranes, molecules, and organelles Nucleus - contains hereditary material, or chromosomes Chromosomes - Structures in nucleus containing genes that transmit traits through generations (humans have 23 pairs, other animals have more) Critical Acids (DNA &amp;amp; RNA) Structure Deoxyribonucleic Acid (DNA) - nucleic acid used to store genetic information</description></item><item><title>ANT100: Lecture_17</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/ant100/ant100-lecture_17/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/ant100/ant100-lecture_17/</guid><description>Primates February 4
==Key features of primates== Grasping hands and feet Collarbone (clavicle) Radius and ulna Forward facing eyes and stereoscopic vision Body size: double the size -&amp;gt; 8x heavier Smaller animals have greater heat loss than larger animals Primate Activity Patterns Nocturnal: active at night Diurnal: active during the day Crepuscular: active at dawn and dusk Cathemeral: active any time of day or night Primate Diet Variety of fruits, insects, flowers, and leaves [eat only leaves require special gut adaptations] Larger primates typically eat more leaves while smaller primates eat more insects Primate Habitats Tropical rainforests, dry forests, deserts, and savannas; primary vs.</description></item><item><title>ANT100: Lecture_18</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/ant100/ant100-lecture_18/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/ant100/ant100-lecture_18/</guid><description>Primate and Hominin Evolution February 11
Time was divided into geological eras known as epochs Paleocene (65.5 – 55.8 MYA) Climate: hotter, more humid than modern-day
Plesiadapaformes/Plesiadapids (Paleocene primate-like mammals) Size of shrew to small dog; likely solitary; nocturnal; quadrupedal; good sense of smell; diet of insects and seeds; was considered a primate because of teeth and limbs (adapted those for arboreal lifestyle)</description></item><item><title>ANT100: Lecture_19</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/ant100/ant100-lecture_19/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/ant100/ant100-lecture_19/</guid><description>Human Evolution February 25
Rise of the genus homo Species in the genus: homo: habilis; rudolfensis; erectus; ergaster; heidelbergensis; antecessor; neanderthalensis; floresiensis; sapiens (us)
First evolved in Africa; most date 2.4-1.8 MYA; first fossil member is Homo habilis (handy man); named such due to possible stone tools discovered nearby; some suggest H. habilis is actually multiple species ==Homo Habilis== [Tanzania, Kenya, and Ethiopia (2.3-1.6 MYA)] Species designation - brain size and association with stone tools Skeletal morphology similar to contemporaneous australopithecines May represent 2 or more different species (H.</description></item><item><title>ANT100: Lecture_2</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/ant100/ant100-lecture_2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/ant100/ant100-lecture_2/</guid><description>Culture Difference &amp;amp; Prejudice What is the &amp;ldquo;difference&amp;rdquo; Race is an example of difference Culture difference is not given biologically, it is given by culture itself and history Difference is dynamic and changing, prejudice it has to do with difference and similarities Prejudice &amp;ndash; (偏见) people don&amp;rsquo;t hate all people that are different. Culture and Language Universal patterns Communication, imagination, identity Cultural &amp;ndash; What we learn from each other vs.</description></item><item><title>ANT100: Lecture_20</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/ant100/ant100-lecture_20/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/ant100/ant100-lecture_20/</guid><description>Forensic Anthropology &amp;amp; Archaeology March 4
Sexual Variation Just as morphological variation in humans, we have a fantastic variety of gender and sexual identities and biologies, respectively Biological sex is a function of chromosomes, gonads, hormones, and genitals Old days: external male genitalia or female genitalia; Now: XY (male) or XX (female); Trisomy (XXX, XXY, XYY); Pentasomy (including XXXX, XXYY, XXXXX, XXXXY and XYYYY) New days: all kinds of external and internal parts Biological sex is incredibly variable and complicated in plants and animals; not just ours Gymnopthalmus: Unisexual species: only “girls”, reproducing through parthenogenesis (non-sperm reproduction) Seen in hundreds of insect and animal, but not in humans until done so in a lab by accident; Sequential hermaphroditism (顺序雌雄同体) - individual changes sex at some point in its life (male to female, female to male, female&amp;gt;hermaphrodite) Develop in males first, and when they mature, some become females.</description></item><item><title>ANT100: Lecture_21</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/ant100/ant100-lecture_21/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/ant100/ant100-lecture_21/</guid><description>ARCH Intro ==Chris Gosden==’s Prehistory: A Very Short Introduction Rethink prehistory in a non-progressivist framework; the past is contested; examples from parts of the world you are unlikely to have heard about Implies people without writing are unchanging Written histories imply progress, All peoples have ways of recording their histories For Gosden, prehistory is long ==history (about process, not events)== Agriculture Older ideas: cultural evolution: progressive, “onwards and upwards” ==Gordon Childe==: The Neolithic “revolution”; Neolithic = “New Stone Age”, changed every facet of human life.</description></item><item><title>ANT100: Lecture_22</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/ant100/ant100-lecture_22/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/ant100/ant100-lecture_22/</guid><description>Archaeological methods and Humanity&amp;rsquo;s African Origins March 11
Archaeological Methods The methods we use influence the kinds of data that we can collect; methods shaped by research question How methods influence interpretation Ex: The Boardwalk site: using screens found evidence of fish bones at a coastal site, which was previously believed to not have fish bones when excavated without screens Interpretation - how we interpret the past determined by evidence, but also our theoretical perspective; our idea, and research questions Archeological Evidence ==Artifacts; sites; features; ecofacts== (plant remains/animal remains); stratigraphy(地层学); dates; matrix (the sediment making up the site); chemical Signature (example of residue of plant remains)</description></item><item><title>ANT100: Lecture_23</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/ant100/ant100-lecture_23/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/ant100/ant100-lecture_23/</guid><description>Europe, Asia, Africa Palaeolithic and Neolithic March 18
Middle Paleolithic: 200KYA – 40KYA H. neanderthalensis (Europe and Near East); H. denisova (Asia); H. floresiensis (Asia); ==H. sapiens== (start in Africa, but spread throughout the world) For H. sapiens: overall, long distance of material suggests interconnectedness of people; shift towards blades and composite tools Mousterian: Flakes made using Levallois technique; flakes retouched into many tool types: sidescrapers, points, denticulates; associated with Neanderthals Levallois Technique: prepared core; skill and time needed; produces several flakes Upper Paleolithic: 50-40KYA until approx.</description></item><item><title>ANT100: Lecture_24</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/ant100/ant100-lecture_24/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/ant100/ant100-lecture_24/</guid><description>Australia and the Americas March 25
Peopling of Australia: 50-60KYA Older than stated in textbook, due to recent evidence Wallace Line means boat travel (first peoples came by boat, there was no land bridge in recent history) What do these early sites look like? Rock shelters; seem to be among earliest peoples in the world to process grasses into flour and meal Built landscapes and plant and animal management: shellfish harvesting; most commonly used fire to remove unwanted brush/vegetation Rock Art: oldest rock art ca.</description></item><item><title>ANT100: Lecture_25</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/ant100/ant100-lecture_25/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/ant100/ant100-lecture_25/</guid><description>Urbanism April 1
V. Gordon Childe:
The Urban Revolution Close relationship between city and the state, according to Childe 10 criteria for early states; size and large population; full-time specialists; agricultural surplus; monumental architecture; long-distance trade; writing; ruling elites and class-based; taxation; control of labour; some traits present in non-cities, and some cities don’t have these traits Chris Gosden and Aggregation: urbanism as a process; part of aggregation: linked to power (sacred and secular); not necessarily social inequality; competing lineages; example of Talianky, a Neolithic aggregation site on the Russian Steppe Catalhoyuk: 9100 to 7700 years ago; in central Turkey; farmers, but also rely on hunting animals; like Abu Hereyra and Natufian, people practice sub-floor burial; no indication of social inequality; households are the centre of production Urbanism in Mesopotamia: Tigris and Euphrates rivers (modern-day Iraq); first sites agreed to be cities; structures built out of reeds and mud; fertile soils allowed for large-scale agriculture; process of urbanization begins ca.</description></item><item><title>ANT100: Lecture_26</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/ant100/ant100-lecture_26/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/ant100/ant100-lecture_26/</guid><description>The present past April 8
The past is often contested
“Who controls the past controls the future; who controls the present controls the past” - George Orwell, 1984
What is Heritage? “Heritage is a property – something that is passed down from previous generations. Cultural heritage consists of the cultures, values, and traditions of a particular community, group, or nation. Cultural heritage can be comprised of tangible things such as artifacts, artwork, and buildings, or intangible things, such as language, dances, and stories.</description></item><item><title>ANT100: Lecture_3&amp;4</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/ant100/ant100-lecture_34/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/ant100/ant100-lecture_34/</guid><description>Signifying Reality Dive under the surface, and ask question about the &amp;ldquo;obvious&amp;rdquo;
Readings All languages appear to have nouns and verbs Humans are programmed to easily process certain kind of language rules Need not be spoken Its independent of the way we express it Language need not to be communicated (internal speech) Reflects the way we speak with others Other understanding of the world is aided by both the internal speech &amp;amp; social understanding Linguistic and semiotic anthropology are disciplines that study the role of signs in human cultural and society ==How signs represent our world (semiotics)== Human&amp;rsquo;s reality is constructed by our use of signs</description></item><item><title>ANT100: Lecture_5&amp;6</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/ant100/ant100-lecture_56/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/ant100/ant100-lecture_56/</guid><description>Religion &amp;amp; Identity What&amp;rsquo;s really real
Reading Authoritative definition of religion is hard to come up Includes conceptions of non0human and superhuman beings and forces that are in social and cultural relationships with humans Religion is a loose system of different kinds of concepts, roles, and behaviours, each includes &amp;ldquo;Spiritual&amp;rdquo; being(s) and/or force(s) Roles for human specialists Behavioural or &amp;ldquo;ritual&amp;rdquo; activity Language or religious speech as part of - or itself being - ritual activity Anthropological attitude to religion Goal: not to judge or to establish truth or falsehood</description></item><item><title>ANT100: Lecture_7</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/ant100/ant100-lecture_7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/ant100/ant100-lecture_7/</guid><description>Relatedness Readings A society must assign individual names, identities, roles, interests, and statuses. This entails establishing and perpetuating corporate groups. Kinship is one universal way of making and maintaining such groups. (not the only way) 3 principles of kinship system: Marriage; Residence; Descent (血统) Other sub-issues such as gender, domestic, and property relations with the interconnections they make significantly shape the experience of the society. In addition, non-kinship characters can also be sued to create corporate groups Sex/gender, age, race, common interest, class/socio-economic status.</description></item><item><title>ANT100: Lecture_8</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/ant100/ant100-lecture_8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/ant100/ant100-lecture_8/</guid><description>Universal and Particular moral values Universal (absolute) and particular (cultural) moral values Universal (absolute) moral values - believing that these exists as the opposite of moral relativism Not necessarily opposite of cultural relativism, it allows for moral universals and moral particulars Cultural and moral relativism ==Moral relativism== - there are no absolute values, (what is good or evil depends on the culture)
Anthropologist is against moral relativism ==Cultural relativism== - assumptions and behaviours mean different things in different cultures</description></item><item><title>ANT100: Lecture_9&amp;11</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/ant100/ant100-lecture_911/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/ant100/ant100-lecture_911/</guid><description>The Economy Reading Every society has political functions that must be fulfilled The various functions can be encapsulated into social order and social control Social control is achieved by Externalized controls Internalized controls All members of a society are informal agents of social control on each other Politics is the exercise of power, with different sources and differ qualities Authority Persuasion Coercion Depending on the different level of political integration, political systems may be distinguished: Band Tribe Chiefdom State Socialites must meet and solve recurrent social problems, 2 boarder lines Determination and punishment of guilt Restoration of social harmony Politiical independence sometimes bring economic independence (no always) Relations of ownership, control, production, and export did not change hands Consequences of economic dependence Poverty, low standards of living, and mainly rural populations and agricultural production General approach of development: modernization theory, dependency/word system theory Draw back: displacement of people, social disorganization, declining health and living standards for some, acculturation and deculturation, destruction of the environment The base and superstructure Human survival requires ways to provision people with food, clothing and ways to change the environment to support human Human work in groups to accomplish this Interested in how specific policies function in &amp;ldquo;the field&amp;rdquo; and their pursue of ethnographic method Results are less generalizable, but ore true to life ==Marxist Model== Base (relations of production, means of production) Natural resources, tools, mines, factories, offices, infrastructure (concrete things ) Superstructure (government, family, religion, education, culture) Social relationships required by the economy, different relations of production in different economic systems (system of production) Base and superstructure is always correlated Each economic system correlates with a different kind of superstructure Economic systems can be arranged historically in terms of appearancez Economic systems and their history Foraging (hunting, and gathering) Minimal manipulation of the environment [50-40,000 ago]</description></item><item><title>CSC111: 10_Selection and Insertion</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/csc111/csc111-10_selection-and-insertion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/csc111/csc111-10_selection-and-insertion/</guid><description>Selection sort and Insertion Sort Sorted Lists and Binary Search 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 def search(lst: list, item: Any) -&amp;gt; int: &amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;#34;Return whether item appears in this list.&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;#34; for element in lst: if element = item: return True return False This function has a worst-case running time of $\Theta(n)$, where $n$ is the length of lst A more &amp;ldquo;smart&amp;rdquo; way is to compare the searched element with the middle number of an arranged list and decide to continue the search on the left, right, or stop (if found in the middle one) Binary search - &amp;ldquo;binary&amp;rdquo; refers to the fact that at every comparison, the range of elements to check is hailed Implementing binary search (iteratively) Need to keep track of the current search range, use variables: b and e, which divide search in 3 parts lst[0:b] - items that are less than the item being searched for lst[b:e] - the current search range: lst[e:len(lst)] only the items that are greater than the item been searched for First, calculate the midpoint m of the current range Then compare lst[m] against item Stop the lop with lst[b:e] is empty (that is when b&amp;gt;=e) 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 def binary_search(lst: list, item: Any) -&amp;gt; bool: &amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;#34;Return whether tiem is in lst using the binary search algorithem Preconditions: - is_sorted(lst) &amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;#34; b, e = 0, len(lst) while b &amp;lt; e: # Loop invariants assert all(lst[i] &amp;lt; item for i in range (0, b)) assert all(lst[i] &amp;gt; item for i in range (e, len(lst))) m = (b + e) // 2 if item == lst[m]: return True elif item &amp;lt; lst[m]: e = m else: # item &amp;gt; list[m] b = m + 1 # If the loop ends wihtout finding the item return False Running time e - b is initially equals to $n$, the length of the input The loop stops when e - b &amp;lt;= 0 Each iteration, e - b decrease by at least a factor of 2 Putting it together get $RT &amp;lt; 1 + \log_2n$ which is $\Theta(\log n)$, much better than linear search $\Theta(n)$ Selection Sort Given a collection of unsorted elements, repeatedly extract the smallest element form the collection, building up a sorted list from this</description></item><item><title>CSC111: 11_Divide-and-Conquer</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/csc111/csc111-11_divide-and-conquer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/csc111/csc111-11_divide-and-conquer/</guid><description>Divide and Conquer Algorithms Introduction to Divide-and-Conquer Algorithms Divide-and-conquer algorithms - splitting the task up into subtasks can make it easier to manage
Given the problem input, split it up into two or more smaller subparts with the same structure
(Given a list to sort, split it up into two or more smaller lists)
Recursively run the algorithm on each subpart separately
(Recursively run the sorting algorithm on each smaller list separately)</description></item><item><title>CSC111: 12_Average-Case Running Time</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/csc111/csc111-12_average-case-running-time/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/csc111/csc111-12_average-case-running-time/</guid><description>Average-Case Running Time In practice worst-case running time analysis can be misleading, with a variety of algorithms having a poor worst-case performance still yet performing well on the vast majority of inputs.
Let func be a program, for each $n \in \N$, define set $I_{func, n}$ to be the set of all inputs so func of size $n$.
$$ WC_{func}(n) = \max {\text{running time of executing } \texttt{func}(x)~ |~ x \in I_{func, c} } $$ Average-case running time of func is defined as the function $Avg_{\texttt{func}}: \N \to \R^+$ where</description></item><item><title>CSC111: 1_Linked Lists</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/csc111/csc111-1_linked-lists/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/csc111/csc111-1_linked-lists/</guid><description>Linked Lists Building Blocks of Linked Lists Python use array-based list implementations (elements are stored in consecutive locations)
Indexing fast $\Theta(1)$, while inserting/deleting slow worst-case running time $\Theta(n)$
The python interpreter need find a memory space enough to store the consecutive datas Linked List - has the same public itnerface as a list, but have a different private implementation that do not have the long running time as lists.</description></item><item><title>CSC111: 2_Induction and Recursion</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/csc111/csc111-2_induction-and-recursion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/csc111/csc111-2_induction-and-recursion/</guid><description>Induction and Recursion Proof by Induction The induction principle applies to universal statements over the natural numbers
Using chain of implications The base case is a poof that the stamens is True for the first natural number $n=0$, i.e. prove that $P(n)$ holds
The inductive step is a poof that for all $k \in \mathbb{N}$ if $P(k)$ is True then $P(k+1)$ is also True $$ \forall k \in \mathbb{N},~ P(k) \quad \Rightarrow \quad P(k+1) $$</description></item><item><title>CSC111: 3_Trees</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/csc111/csc111-3_trees/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/csc111/csc111-3_trees/</guid><description>Trees Definition and Terminology Tree data structure to represent hierarchical data its a recursive data structure. A tree is either:
Empty Have a root value connected to any number pf the trees, called the subtrees of the tree Size of a tree is the number of values in the tree.
Leaf &amp;ndash; a value with no subtrees
Internal value (opposite to leaf), its a value that has at least one subtree</description></item><item><title>CSC111: 4_Binary Search Trees</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/csc111/csc111-4_binary-search-trees/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/csc111/csc111-4_binary-search-trees/</guid><description>Binary Search Trees Define a new abstract data type (ADT) that is an extension of the Set ADT that allows for duplicates Multiset Data: an unordered collection of values, allowing duplicates Operations: get size, insert a value, remove one occurrence of a specified value, check membership in the multiset Using list to implement the Multiset ADT Searching would have the $RT$ of $\Theta(n)$ if simply append new items to the list Using binary search algorithm would improve the $RT$ to $\Theta(\log n)$ Binary Search Tree definitions Binary tree is a tree in which every item has two (possibly empty) subtrees, which are labelled its left and right subtrees.</description></item><item><title>CSC111: 5_Abstract Syntax Trees</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/csc111/csc111-5_abstract-syntax-trees/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/csc111/csc111-5_abstract-syntax-trees/</guid><description>Abstract Syntax Trees Strings have a linear (a sequence of characters) Programs have a naturally recursive structure. Most data types have the potential to be nested, which mega the program recursive First step Python interpreter takes is to create Abstract Syntax Tree (AST) to represent the program The Expr class Expression - a piece of code which is meant to be evaluated, returning the value of an expression Every expression would use a different attribute, so not attribute in abstract class 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 class Expr: &amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;#34;An abstract class representting a Python expression&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;#34; def evaluate(self) -&amp;gt; Any: &amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;#34;Return the *value* of this expression The returned value should be the result of hwo this expression would be evaluated by the Python interpreter &amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;#34; raise NotImplementedError Num numerical literals Literals are the bases cases of leaves, of an AST 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 class Num(Expr): &amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;#34;A numeric literal.</description></item><item><title>CSC111: 6_Graph Class</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/csc111/csc111-6_graph-class/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/csc111/csc111-6_graph-class/</guid><description>The Graph Class Terminologies Graph - a pair of sets $G = (V, E)$, where $G$ is the graph itself, $V$ is the vertex and $E$ is the edge set
Vertex $V$ - a set of objects, each element is called a vertex of the graph, while the set $V$ itself is called the set of vertices of the graph [rep collection of points] Edge $E$ - a set of pairs of objects from $V$, where each pair ${v_1, v_2}$ is a set of distinct vertices, called the edge of the graph ($v_1, v_2 \in V, \and v_1 \neq v_2$) [rep relationships] Order does not matter in the pairs, (${v_1, v_2} = {v_2, v_1}$) Ex.</description></item><item><title>CSC111: 7_Graphs in Python</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/csc111/csc111-7_graphs-in-python/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/csc111/csc111-7_graphs-in-python/</guid><description>Graphs in Python Representing Graphs in Python The _Vertex class Implement graph as a node-based data structure vertex - node; edge - implicit as a variable in the vertex node Restrictions on edges: cannot have a vertex with an edge to itself AND all edges are symmetric 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 from __future__ import annotations from typing import Any class _Vertex: &amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;#34;A vertex in a graph Instance Attributes: - item: The data stored in this vertex - neighbours: The vertices that are adjacent to this vertex Representation Invariants: - self not in self.</description></item><item><title>CSC111: 8_Cycles and Trees</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/csc111/csc111-8_cycles-and-trees/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/csc111/csc111-8_cycles-and-trees/</guid><description>Cycles and Trees A &amp;ldquo;Lower Bound&amp;rdquo; for connectivity What is the minimum number of edges required in a connected graph. Any connected graph $G = (V, E)$ must have $|E| \ge |V| - 1$ However, it is hard to prove this. Cycles Cycle - Let $G = (V, E)$ be a graph, a cycle in $G$ is a sequence of vertices $v_0, \dots, v_k$ satisfying the following conditions</description></item><item><title>CSC111: 9_Computing Spanning Tree</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/csc111/csc111-9_computing-spanning-tree/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/csc111/csc111-9_computing-spanning-tree/</guid><description>Computing Spanning Trees Spanning trees and the problem specification Let $G = (V, E)$ be a connected graph. Let $G&amp;rsquo; = (V, E&amp;rsquo;)$ be another graph with the same vertex set as $G$, and where $E&amp;rsquo; \subset E$. Spanning tree - in the above case, $G&amp;rsquo;$ is a spanning tree of G Gaol: Implement the Graph method that computes a spanning tree for the graph. 1.</description></item><item><title>MAT223: 11_Range &amp; Nullspace</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/mat223/mat223-11_range-nullspace/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/mat223/mat223-11_range-nullspace/</guid><description>Range and Nullspace of a Linear Transformation Range and Nullspace of a Linear Transformation Range - the range (or image) of a linear transformation $T: V \to W$ is the set of vectors $T$ can output, which is $$ \text{range}(T) = \left{ \vec{y} \in W: \vec{y} = T\vec{x}~ \text{ for some }~ \vec{x} \in V \right} $$
The range of a linear transformation is the exact same as the definition of the range of a function</description></item><item><title>MAT223: 12_Inverse Functions and Matrices</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/mat223/mat223-12_inverse-functions-and-matrices/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/mat223/mat223-12_inverse-functions-and-matrices/</guid><description>Inverse Functions and Inverse Matrices Invertible functions Identity Function - Let $X$ be a set the identity function with domain and codomain $X$, notated $id: X \to X$, is the function satisfying, for all $x \in X$ $$ \text{id}(x) = x $$
Identity function is the function that nodes nothing to tis input A function is invertible if it can be undone. (If there exists an inverse function that when composed with the original function produces the identity function and vice versa)</description></item><item><title>MAT223: 13&amp;14_Change of Basis II and Determinations</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/mat223/mat223-1314_change-of-basis-ii-and-determinations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/mat223/mat223-1314_change-of-basis-ii-and-determinations/</guid><description>Change of Basis II Change of Basis matrix - Let $\mathcal{A}, \mathcal{B}$ be basis for $\R^n$. The matrix $M$ is called a change of basis matrix (which converts from $\mathcal{A}$ to $\mathcal{B}$) if for all $\vec{x} \in \R^n$ $$ M \left[ \vec{x} \right]\mathcal{A} = \left[ \vec{x} \right]\mathcal{B} $$ Notationally, $[\mathcal{B} \gets \mathcal{A}]$ stands for the change of basis matrix converting from $\mathcal{A}$ to $\mathcal{B}$. Write $M = [\mathcal{B} \gets \mathcal{A}]$</description></item><item><title>MAT223: 15&amp;16_Eigenvectors and Diagonalization</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/mat223/mat223-1516_eigenvectors-and-diagonalization/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/mat223/mat223-1516_eigenvectors-and-diagonalization/</guid><description>Eigenvalues, Eigenvectors and Diagonalization Eigenvalues and Eigenvectors Eigenvector - Let $X$ be a linear transformation or a matrix. An eigenvector for $X$ is a non-zero vector that doesn&amp;rsquo;t change the directions when $X$ is applied. That is $\vec{v} \neq \vec{0}$ is an eigenvector for $X$: $$ X \vec{v} = \lambda \vec{v} $$ Eigenvalue - is a scaler $\lambda$, of $X$ corresponding to the eigenvector $\vec{v}$ Finding Eigenvectors Let $M$ be a square matrix.</description></item><item><title>MAT223: 1_Sets and Vectors</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/mat223/mat223-1_sets-and-vectors/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/mat223/mat223-1_sets-and-vectors/</guid><description>Week 1 Sets and sets-builder notation Set &amp;ndash; An unordered collection of distinct objects Elements &amp;ndash; things inside a set, use the symbol $\in$ to represent that some specific element is inside a set; and uses $\notin$ to show that the element is not inside the set Sets can contain mixture of objects, and is named with capital letters An empty set contains no elements, and is written with $\emptyset$ Sets and Interval notation Close bracket: $[a, b] = {x \in \mathbb{R} \mid a \le x \le b}$, Open bracket: $(a, b) = {x \in \mathbb{R} \mid a &amp;lt; x &amp;lt; b}$ Set operations Subsets &amp;amp; Superset &amp;ndash; if set $B$ is a subset of $A$, its written as $B \subset A$ $\subsetneq$ means a subset of, but maynot be equal; while $\subseteq$ means that its a set of &amp;amp; equal In $B \subseteq A$, if all $b \in B$ and $b \in A$, then $A$ is a superset of $B$ Set equality &amp;ndash; $A = B$ if and only if $A \subseteq B$ and $B \subseteq A$ Prove: $(\forall a \in A, a \in B) \quad \and \quad (\forall b \in B, b \in A)$ Set-builder notation If $X$ is a set, define a subset: $Y = {a \in X:\text{some rule involving}~ a}$ Union &amp;ndash; $X \cup Y = {a : a \in X~ \text{or}~ a \in Y}$ Intersection &amp;ndash; $X \cap Y = {a : a \in X~ \text{and}~ a \in Y}$ Vectors Vector - An arrow inside a coordinate system, rooted at the origin, associated with a set of coordinates Vector coordinates notation: $\vec{v}=\begin{bmatrix} \alpha\\beta \end{bmatrix}$ (column vector) It models a relationship between pointsssssssss Scalar &amp;ndash; numbers that modules a relationship between quantities The $\left | \vec{a} \right |$ represents the magnitude of the vector $\vec{a}$ (norm of $\vec{a}$).</description></item><item><title>MAT223: 2_Vector, Lines, and Planes</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/mat223/mat223-2_vector-lines-and-planes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/mat223/mat223-2_vector-lines-and-planes/</guid><description>Vectors, Lines, and Planes Row Reduction (Gauss-Jordan Elimination) Augmented matrix: $\begin{bmatrix} 1 &amp;amp; 2 &amp;amp; 1 &amp;amp; 0\ 2 &amp;amp; 3 &amp;amp; 1 &amp;amp; 1\ 3 &amp;amp; 1 &amp;amp; 2 &amp;amp; 0 \end{bmatrix}$ from the System: $\left{\begin{matrix} &amp;amp; x+2y+z = 0 \ &amp;amp; 2x+3y+z = 1 \ &amp;amp; 3x+y+2z = 0\end{matrix}\right.$
First phase: work down from top, from left from right
Top row stays the same (as the tool row) that contains the pivot column $\begin{bmatrix} 1 &amp;amp; 2 &amp;amp; 1 &amp;amp; 0\ 0 &amp;amp; -1 &amp;amp; -1 &amp;amp; 1\ 0 &amp;amp; -5 &amp;amp; -1 &amp;amp; 0 \end{bmatrix}$ $Row 2 - 2 \cdot Row1 \ Row3 - 3 \cdot Row1$</description></item><item><title>MAT223: 3_Linear Dependence</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/mat223/mat223-3_linear-dependence/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/mat223/mat223-3_linear-dependence/</guid><description>Spans, Translated Spans, and Linear Independence/Dependence Span defintion Span - the span of a set of vectors $V$ is the set of all linear combinations of vectors in $V$. $$ \text{span}V = {\vec{v}: \vec{v} = \alpha_1 \vec{v}_1 + \alpha_2 \vec{v}_2 ~&amp;hellip;~ + \alpha_n \vec{v}_n ~\text{for some}~ \alpha_1, \alpha_2,~&amp;hellip;~, \alpha_n \in \R } $$
span${} = {\vec{0} }$ Let $\vec{a}=\begin{bmatrix} 1 \ 2 \ 1 \end{bmatrix}, \vec{b}=\begin{bmatrix} 0 \ 1 \ 0 \end{bmatrix}, \vec{c}=\begin{bmatrix} 1 \ 1 \ 2 \end{bmatrix}$.</description></item><item><title>MAT223: 4_Dot Products &amp; Normal</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/mat223/mat223-4_dot-products-normal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/mat223/mat223-4_dot-products-normal/</guid><description>Dot Products &amp;amp; Normal Forms Dot Product Sometimes called as the &amp;ldquo;scaler product&amp;rdquo; because it produces a scaler
Let $\vec{a}, \vec{b}$ be vectors rooted at the same point and let $\theta$ denote the smaller of the two angles between them ($0 \le \theta \le \pi$), the geometric definition of dot product is $$ \vec{a} \cdot \vec{b} = \left|\vec{a}\right| \left|\vec{b}\right| \cos \theta $$
$\vec{x}= (2,3), \quad \left|\vec{x}\right|=\sqrt{2^2 + 3^2} =\sqrt{13}$</description></item><item><title>MAT223: 5_Projections</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/mat223/mat223-5_projections/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/mat223/mat223-5_projections/</guid><description>Projections and Vector Components Projection Projection - Let $X$ be a set, the projection of the vector $\vec{v}$ onto $X$, written $\text{proj}_X \vec{v}$ is the closest point in $X$ to $\vec{v}$
Intuitively, $\text{proj}{xy} \vec{v}$ is the &amp;ldquo;shadow&amp;rdquo; that $\vec{v}$ would on $\text{proj}{xy}$ if the sun were perpendicular to $X$ If there are two points other as the closest point to $\vec{v}$, OR there are no closest point to $\vec{v}$, then $\text{proj}_X \vec{v}$ is undefined</description></item><item><title>MAT223: 6_Subspaces</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/mat223/mat223-6_subspaces/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/mat223/mat223-6_subspaces/</guid><description>Subspaces and Bases Subspace A subspace is a smaller set within a vector space. It is similar to the set contains its subset. In other words, subspace is the non-empty subset of a vector space.
A non-empty subset $V \subseteq \R^n$ is called a subspace if for all $\vec{u}, \vec{v} \in V$ and all scalars $k$:
$\vec{u} + \vec{v} \in \mathcal{V} \quad \and \quad k\vec{u} \in \mathcal{V}$</description></item><item><title>MAT223: 7_Matrix</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/mat223/mat223-7_matrix/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/mat223/mat223-7_matrix/</guid><description>Matrix Coefficient matrix Every system (or single) of linear equations can be rewritten as a matrix equation of the form
$A\vec{x} = \vec{b}$, where $A$ is a coefficient matrix, $\vec{x}$ is a column vector of variables, and $\vec{b}$ is a column vector of constants
$$ A: \quad \left{\begin{matrix} x+2y-2z = -15 \ 2x+y-5zz = -21 \ x-4y+z = 18\end{matrix}\right. \quad \text{can be writen as} \quad \begin{bmatrix} 1 &amp;amp; 2 &amp;amp; -2\ 2 &amp;amp; 1 &amp;amp; -5 \ 1 &amp;amp; -4 &amp;amp; 1 \end{bmatrix} \begin{bmatrix} x \ y \ x \end{bmatrix} = \begin{bmatrix} -15 \ -21 \ 18 \end{bmatrix} $$</description></item><item><title>MAT223: 8_Change of Basis</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/mat223/mat223-8_change-of-basis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/mat223/mat223-8_change-of-basis/</guid><description>Coordinates &amp;amp; Change of Basis Basis for a subspace $\mathcal{V}$ is a linearly independent spanning subspace Dimension of a subspace $\mathcal{V}$ is the size of a basis for $\mathcal{V}$ (number of basis vectors) Find a basis and the dimension of $W = \text{span} \left{ \begin{bmatrix}0 \ 0 \ 0\end{bmatrix}, \begin{bmatrix}1 \ -2 \ -1\end{bmatrix}, \begin{bmatrix}2 \ -4 \ -2\end{bmatrix}, \begin{bmatrix}-2 \ 5 \ 3\end{bmatrix}, \begin{bmatrix}3 \ -6 \ -2\end{bmatrix} \right}$ Find a maximal linearly independent subset using matrix $$ \begin{bmatrix} 0 &amp;amp; 1 &amp;amp; 2 &amp;amp;-2 &amp;amp;3 \ 0 &amp;amp; -2 &amp;amp; -4 &amp;amp; 5 &amp;amp; -6 \0 &amp;amp; -1 &amp;amp; -2 &amp;amp; 3 &amp;amp; -2 \end{bmatrix} \quad \text{RREF} \quad \begin{bmatrix} 0 &amp;amp; 1 &amp;amp; 2 &amp;amp;0 &amp;amp;0\ 0 &amp;amp; 0 &amp;amp; 0 &amp;amp; 1 &amp;amp; 0 \0 &amp;amp; 0 &amp;amp; 0 &amp;amp; 0&amp;amp; 1 \end{bmatrix} $$ Column 2, 4, 5 are linearly independent $$ \mathcal{B}=\left{ \begin{bmatrix}1 \ -2 \ -1\end{bmatrix}, \begin{bmatrix}-2 \ 5 \ 3\end{bmatrix}, \begin{bmatrix}3 \ -6 \ -2\end{bmatrix} \right} $$ $\mathcal{B}$ is a basis of $W$ and dim$(W) = 3$, then $W = \R^3$</description></item><item><title>MAT223: 9&amp;10_Linear Transformations</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/mat223/mat223-910_linear-transformations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/mat223/mat223-910_linear-transformations/</guid><description>Linear Transformations Transformation (map) - another word for a function, used to describe changing vectors $$ F: R^n \to R^m \quad \text{defined by} \quad \begin{bmatrix} x \ y \end{bmatrix} \mapsto \begin{bmatrix} x~(&amp;hellip;) \ y~(&amp;hellip;) \end{bmatrix} $$ For $n, m \in \N$, and $(&amp;hellip;)$ are real number operations for the transformation
The transformation is a set of rules that assigns each vector $\vec{x}$ in $\R^n$ to a vector $T(\vec{x})$ in $\R^m$ The transformation $T: \R^2 \to \R^2$ defined by $\begin{bmatrix} x \ y \end{bmatrix} \mapsto \begin{bmatrix} x+3 \ y \end{bmatrix}$ Image of a Set - Let $L:\R^n \to \R^m$ be a transformation and let $X \subseteq \R^n$ be a set.</description></item><item><title>MGT100: - L1</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/mgt100/mgt100-l1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/mgt100/mgt100-l1/</guid><description>Reading Questions Quizlet
Chapter 1 [[Business]] What activity lies at the heart of every business endeavour? Trade (exchange between buyer and seller) Profit-seeking activities that brings goods and services to the economic market. What are the primary objectives of a not-for-profit organization? Public service &amp;gt; profit, need to raise money for operation Factors of production Identify the four basic inputs to an economic system Natural Resource Capital Human Resource [[Entrepreneurship]] List 4 types of capital Information Tool Technology Physical facilities [[Capitalism|Private enterprise system]] What is an alternative term for the private enterprise system?</description></item><item><title>MGT100: - L2</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/mgt100/mgt100-l2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/mgt100/mgt100-l2/</guid><description>Reading Chapter 5 Small business Describe the characteristics of a small business (by Industry Canada). Independently owned, employees &amp;lt; 100, revenues &amp;lt; $2 million In what industries do small business play a significant role? Provide jobs in construction, agriculture, wholesale trade, services, retail trade Discuss the contributions of small business to the economy What are the 3 key ways small business contribute?</description></item><item><title>MGT100: - L3</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/mgt100/mgt100-l3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/mgt100/mgt100-l3/</guid><description>Reading Role and responsibilities of human resource management What are the five main tasks of a human resource manager? Planning for staffing needs, Recruiting and hiring workers, Providing for training and evaluating performance Deciding on compensation and benefits And overseeing employee separation. What are the three overall objectives of a human resource manager? Providing qualified, well-trained employees for the organization Maximizing employee effectiveness Satisfying individual employee needs through monetary compensation.</description></item><item><title>MGT100: - L4</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/mgt100/mgt100-l4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/mgt100/mgt100-l4/</guid><description>Reading Describe management What is management? Management is the process of achieving organizational goals through people and other resources. The manager’s job is to combine human and technical resources in the best way possible to achieve the company’s goals. Describe the differences in the jobs of top managers, middle managers, and supervisory managers. Top managers develop long-range plans, set a direction for their organization, and inspire all employees to achieve the company’s vision.</description></item><item><title>MGT100: - L5</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/mgt100/mgt100-l5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/mgt100/mgt100-l5/</guid><description>Reading Lecture PDF: [[100 - S5.pdf]] Reasons to study ethics Quick Test Global mail test Case study Contact lens example Outlets vs retail Outlet product vs non-outlet product With outlet product quality vs non-outlet product quality Ashley Madison There is a difference between the personal level of ethics and business level of ethics ★ Responsibility for the leak CTV News caonima Wells Fargo ★ Ethical: benefit the investors Unethical Active Studying Summarize today&amp;rsquo;s lecture [::Most important/focused topic] [::Most difficult part, why, how to resolve] What part I didn&amp;rsquo;t understand, next step actions?</description></item><item><title>MGT100: - L6</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/mgt100/mgt100-l6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/mgt100/mgt100-l6/</guid><description>Reading Chapter 4 National trade ^85660c Why do nations trade? ^e5edd0 Nations trade because trading increases economic growth. Trade provides a new market for products and access to needed resources. Trading makes production and distribution systems more efficient and reduces dependence on the economy of the domestic market. Countries that encourage international trade usually have higher levels of economic activity, employment, and wages than countries that restrict international trade.</description></item><item><title>MGT100: - L7</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/mgt100/mgt100-l7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/mgt100/mgt100-l7/</guid><description>Reading Chapter 15 [[Accounting]] Define accounting. Accounting is the process of measuring, interpreting, and communicating financial information that describes the status and operation of an organization and aids in decision making. Who uses accounting information? Managers in all types of organizations use accounting information to help them plan, assess performance, and control daily and long-term operations. Outside users of accounting information include government officials, investors, creditors, and donors.</description></item><item><title>MGT100: - L8</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/mgt100/mgt100-l8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/mgt100/mgt100-l8/</guid><description>Reading Chapter 9 Employee empowerment What is empowerment? Empowerment is giving employees shared authority and responsibility to make decisions about their work with their managers. What kinds of information can companies provide to employees to help them share decision-making responsibility? One of the best ways to get employees to share decision-making responsibility is for executives to share information about company performance, particularly financial performance. How do employee stock ownership plans and stock options reward employees and encourage empowerment?</description></item><item><title>MGT100: - L9</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/mgt100/mgt100-l9/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/mgt100/mgt100-l9/</guid><description>Reading Lecture PDF: [[100 - S8.pdf]] Government in the economy &amp;amp; society How does government involve in fiscal &amp;amp; monetary policies? Inflation Unemployment Government finances (taxation, deficits) ★ Creating economic environment in which business operate What are the key roles government interact with business Governments as customers of goods &amp;amp; services Governments as regulator of certain business activities Government as a provider of social &amp;amp; business infrastructure Basics of government in Canada for business ★ What does federal &amp;amp; provincial governments obtain revenues through Personal income taxes Corporate income taxes Sales taxes Tariffs &amp;amp; duties Most municipal income comes from property taxes How are powers of different levels of government divided under Constitution Federal government: defense &amp;amp; foreign policy, regional redistribution Provincial governments: post-secondary education, hospitals, highways Municipal (not addressed constitutionally): public health, children’s recreation programs, libraries, transportation Provincial &amp;amp; municipal – social services, education Federal, provincial &amp;amp; municipal – health, policing, environmental protection Government as regulators (why do governments get involved in the economy as regulators) Protection of consumers – setting &amp;amp; revising rules, conducting investigations &amp;amp; enforcement Food &amp;amp; Drug Act – inspection of meat packing plants; only approved pharmaceuticals may be sold Regulating Hazardous Products – bans, appropriate labeling Specially Regulated Industries - Office of the Superintendent of Financial Institutions, Canada Deposit Insurance Corporation – shape financial services industry; Ontario Securities Commission – protecting investors Protecting competition Competition Act makes it illegal for businesses to act to reduce competition – Antitrust laws But isn’t “reducing competition” by gaining market share what business is all about?</description></item><item><title>Private Stuff</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/private/private-note/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/private/private-note/</guid><description>This page doesn&amp;rsquo;t get published!</description></item><item><title>PSY220: Aggression</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy220/psy220-aggression/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy220/psy220-aggression/</guid><description>Aggression An intentional action aimed at doing harm or cause pain to another living being who is motivated to avoid such treatment
Hostile (hot) - intend to harm another person (physically or/and psychologically) motivated by anger and hostility Instrumental (code) - harm for strategic purposes (gain wealth, political gain, protect [[Out-Group#Group Membership|in-group]] value) Most aggression is a combination of both Origins or Aggression Individual differences or personality traits Narcissism - exaggerated feeling of self-importance Machiavellianism - cunning and manipulative, use other people for their own gain Psychopathy - persistent anti-social behavior Gender - man are more physically aggressive, women display more &amp;ldquo;relational aggression&amp;rdquo; (rumor) Biological Factors Genetic factors (warrior gene/MAOA gene) and (crime gene/CDH13) Underdeveloped or damaged brain areas (damage in orbital cortex) Situational factors Social Learning ==Theory==: [[Bob Doll Experiment]] - observing and learning aggression</description></item><item><title>PSY220: Altruism</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy220/psy220-altruism/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy220/psy220-altruism/</guid><description>Cynical &amp;amp; Positive views of Altruism Prosocial Behavior - any act performed with the goal of benefiting another person Altruism - unselfish behavior that benefits others without a regard to consequences for oneself Cynical View One help other because human beings are selfish Social rewards motive - people are motivated to help others to obtain social rewards People are motivated to help others in need to reduce their own distress Inclusive Fitness (evolutionary) Then tendency for people to look out for themselves, their offspring, and their close relatives, together with their offspring, ensuring that their genes survive Evidence: people receive more help from close kin than distant relatives or non-relatives Reciprocal Altruism The behavior whereby someone acts in a manner that temporarily reduces their own fitness while increasing another&amp;rsquo;s fitness, with the expectation that the other will act in similar manner at a later time Positive View 1 Relateness of A and B /=&amp;gt; Benefit to B &amp;gt; Cost to A one help other not out of self-interest, but purely to assist others Empathy The ability to understand and share the feelings of another</description></item><item><title>PSY220: Attitudes</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy220/psy220-attitudes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy220/psy220-attitudes/</guid><description>Attitudes A psychological construct that represents your evaluations (like or dislike) of people, objects, and ideas.
Elements of Attitudes Affect (emotions) ^82a2e2 Cognitions (thoughts) ^bb0a3c Behaviors ^105ac8 Measurements of attitudes Self-reported measures: evaluate on a set of scale (ex. Likert scale $1-10$) [most common] Implicit measures: indirect measure of attitudes that does not involve self-report ex: Response latency test [[Out-Group#Implicit Association Test|IAT]] Measure physiology (change in heart rate&amp;hellip;) Origins Personal experiences Social learning Genetic factor Evolutionary factors Attitudes =/&amp;gt; Behavior Generally, attitude does predict behavior, its just that it isn&amp;rsquo;t always the case.</description></item><item><title>PSY220: Close Relationships</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy220/psy220-close-relationships/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy220/psy220-close-relationships/</guid><description>Close relationships Close Relationships Bonds with family, friends, and/or romantic partners that ties two or more people over an extended time
Psychological health: happier, higher self-satisfaction Physical health: less get sick, less overall health vulnerabilities, lower risk of heart disease, live long Related Study [[Harlow&amp;rsquo;s Monkey]]
Need to belong Need to Belong Human emotional need to affiliate with and be accepted by others</description></item><item><title>PSY220: Group and Culture</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy220/psy220-group-and-culture/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy220/psy220-group-and-culture/</guid><description>Groups Influence on the individual Group A collection of individuals that are interdependent to each other in some degree A collection of individuals who perceive some level of entitativity (a group considers themselves to be a entity with unity and coherence) Ultrasociality - a collective organization with full division of labour 1000 (or more) individuals living together In all other ultrasocial species, most individuals are cloesly related (genetically) Groups are an adaptation that enables humans to be ultrasociality Advantage of group living (evolution + psychological) Protection from predators Easier to obtain resources Assistance in child rearing Defense against other groups Also fulfills the psychological [[Close Relationships#Need to belong|need to belong]] Disadvantage of group living Intergroup competition and status differentials can emerge Dominant and dominated groups can emerge (race, socioeconomic status) Intergroup bias ([[Out-Group#Stereotyping|stereotyping]], [[Out-Group#Prejudice|prejudice]], [[Out-Group#Discrimination|discrimination]]) Zajonc&amp;rsquo;s Model (social facilitation) ★ Answers: do we behave better when others are present</description></item><item><title>PSY220: Morality</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy220/psy220-morality/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy220/psy220-morality/</guid><description>Moral Attitudes Reflection of one&amp;rsquo;s core moral beliefs and conditions of what&amp;rsquo;s right and wrong.
Moral [[Attitudes#Attitudes|attitude]] are more consistent over time Moral attitudes are more resistant to change Moral attitudes are more predictive of behavior Moral attitudes has deeper ties to emotion Measuring moral attitudes &amp;ldquo;To what extend is your position on [attitude object]&amp;rdquo; consequences of moral attitudes Greater political engagement (politics focus on a lot of moral issues) Social &amp;amp; physical distance from those with opposing views Study of moral attitude wiht social distancing Method Participants were gathered with known views on aborsion.</description></item><item><title>PSY220: Out-Group</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy220/psy220-out-group/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy220/psy220-out-group/</guid><description>Group Membership In-group - a social group to which one do belong Out-group - a social group to which one do not belong Generate US vs. THEM which generates: In-group bias (favoritism) Out-group derogation Ex. Differers ways of dividing a group can lead to different biases
Sexism, Racism, Ageism, Homophobia, Ethnocentrism/Xenophobia, Classism (connection to [[Attitudes#Elements of Attitudes|elements of attitude]])</description></item><item><title>PSY220: Persuasion</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy220/psy220-persuasion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy220/psy220-persuasion/</guid><description>Elaboration Likelihood Model Persuasion An attempt to change [[Attitudes#Attitudes|attitudes]]
How can one persuade people, ==Theory==: [[Elaboration Likelihood Model]] ★ Central vs Peripheral Routes Which route to make depends on 2 factors Motivation: People need a reason to pay attention to the given message Ability: People need to be able to evaluate the message Motivation &amp;amp; Ability Process Factors Promoting Attitude Change HIGH - Personally relevant - Knowledge in domain - Personally responsible [[Elaboration Likelihood Model#Central Systematic route]] Quality of argument LOW - Not personally relevant - Distracted or tired - Message incomplete or hard to understand [[Elaboration Likelihood Model#Peripheral Heuristic route]] - Source attractiveness - # and length of arguments - Consensus Route to Persuation Stuy</description></item><item><title>PSY220: Self</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy220/psy220-self/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy220/psy220-self/</guid><description>Characteristics of Self Distinct entity, separated from other things or people Contains multiple sets of beliefs Organizes knowledge and information about one&amp;rsquo;s self Influences how a person think, feel, and behave Social Psychology Perspective Concept coined by [[William James]] The self is inherently a social construct The concept is derived from others or one&amp;rsquo;s relationship to others The self would be influenced by the [[Context]] There are 4 major components that construct the social self Self-Concept Self ★ Self is a concept, a set of beliefs and perceptions one have about themselves</description></item><item><title>PSY220: Social Influence</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy220/psy220-social-influence/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy220/psy220-social-influence/</guid><description>Social Influence The ways people affect one another (changes in [[Attitudes#Attitudes|attitude]], beliefs, feelings) resulting from the comments, actions or mere presence of others.
Can vary along a continuum 1 2 3 4 5 6 [Conformity] [Compliance] [Obedience] | | | | | | | | | [Low] | --------------------------------------------------------------------| [High] How explicit is the pressure from others [[#Conformity]] - changing one&amp;rsquo;s behavior of beliefs in response to real or imagined pressure from others (norms) Ex.</description></item><item><title>PSY230: Biological Perspective</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy230/psy230-biological-perspective/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy230/psy230-biological-perspective/</guid><description>The Biological Basis Eysenck&amp;rsquo;s Model of Personality Personality traits determined by Biological and environmental factors 2 Aspect to biological: heritability and physiological substrates Substrates: hormones and cortical arousal Used criterion analysis, with the goal of having a small number of factors Broken down to 3 traits: extroversion, neuroticism, pscychoticism Developed around the same time as the [[Big-Five Model]] Argued that there are a healthier people and a less healthy population, based on reaction to stress Problem: problematic research method, leading to racism confusion regarding genetic IQ differences Biopsycholoscial Theory ^41c87f</description></item><item><title>PSY230: Developmental Perspective</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy230/psy230-developmental-perspective/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy230/psy230-developmental-perspective/</guid><description>Early Development The earliest people we see in our lives shape what we are
Builds expectations for future relationship Teach human what to expect and how to handle relationships in life Objective Relation Theory ==Theory==: Psychodynamic - [[P&amp;amp;T - Chapter 1#Object Relations Theory]]
Elements of satisfaction and fractions exist in all relationship See the complicated part of caregivers Lead to contradictory feelings in relationships Can lead to feelings of love and hate Need to distinguish between parts of a love object and the whole person Healthy development requires integrating the good and the bad parts of the object - in particular other people People have internal representation of the other people (the &amp;ldquo;parts&amp;rdquo; that either good or bad) Stored in the unconscious part of one&amp;rsquo;s self Unconsciously influence an individual and predicts their behavior in later adulthood Attachment Theory ==Theory==: [[Attachment Theory]]</description></item><item><title>PSY230: Personality Assessments</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy230/psy230-personality-assessments/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy230/psy230-personality-assessments/</guid><description>Personality Consistent behavior patterns and intra-personal processes originating within the individual 人格是构成一个人的思想 情感和行为的特有模式 包含一个人区别与他们的稳定而统一的心理品质 气质(temperament): 与生俱来的 无好坏之分 无到的评价的意义；具有稳定性 跨活动的一致性 [most unconscious; mostly nature] Choleric, Sanguine, Phlegmatic, Melancholic (couldn&amp;rsquo;t get stable result for myself) 性格(character): 表现为个人的道德品格和行为的风格 能够进行道德评价 [nature and nurture] 人格 (personality) [mostly nurture] 独特性，稳定性，综合性，功能性 Objective Tests Objective Tests Administering a standard set of items, each answered using a limited set of responses options.</description></item><item><title>PSY230: Psychodynamic Perspective</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy230/psy230-psychodynamic-perspective/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy230/psy230-psychodynamic-perspective/</guid><description>Also referred to the [[Psychoanalysis]] theory
Sigmund Freud [[Sigmund Freud]]
In 1887 opened a private practice to focus on nervous disorders (hysteria) with [[Josef Breuer]] Hysteria: a board diagnoses typically given to women exhibiting a wide variety of symptoms ^d89518 Symptoms included anything that act dis-normal Used to be thought as connected to the reproductive system of women Freud argued that Hysteria can be diagnoses to both man and women.</description></item><item><title>PSY230: Trait Perspective</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy230/psy230-trait-perspective/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy230/psy230-trait-perspective/</guid><description>Descriptive Models Gordon Allport [[Gordon Allport]]: father of trait approach
Lexical Approach: all important personality characteristics should be reflected in the language that human use to describe other people [[P&amp;amp;T - Chapter 3.1#Lexical Hypothesis]] Nomothetic Approach: people can be described along a single dimension according to their level of particular trait Most modern assessment approach. Ex. Big-Five Focus on research, not on specific individual Idiographic Approach: identifies the combination of traits that bes accounts for the personality of individual Ex.</description></item><item><title>PSY240: - L1</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy240/psy240-l1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy240/psy240-l1/</guid><description>Readings Describe the principles that have been used to define abnormality and then apply them to determine whether a particular behaviour may meet the definition of abnormal behaviour. According to the statistical view, abnormal behaviour can be determined by how frequently it occurs in the population. Personal distress can indicate the presence of abnormal behaviour The personal dysfunction viewpoint emphasizes that abnormal behaviour interferes with appropriate functioning in a particular situation or environment.</description></item><item><title>PSY240: - L10</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy240/psy240-l10/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy240/psy240-l10/</guid><description>Reading Describe the characteristics of anxiety. There are three distinctive components of emotion: physiology, cognition, and behaviour. When anxiety occurs, we might expect to see increased heart rate and breathing (physiology). The individual may also experience thoughts such as “Something terrible will happen” (cognition), and avoid the anxiety-provoking trigger (behaviour). Anxiety is distinct from panic and fear. Although these are all emotional states, in anxiety the individual feels threatened by a potential future event.</description></item><item><title>PSY240: - L11</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy240/psy240-l11/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy240/psy240-l11/</guid><description>Lecture PDF: Summary [[Specific Phobia]] ==Symptoms==: What are the 3 common [[Specific Phobia#Symptoms|symptoms]] of phobic? Persistent avoidance; Excessive; Interfere life ==Types==: What are the [[Specific Phobia#^303021|5 types]] of common phobia ==Etiology==: What are the 2 models and 2 explanations of phobia? Associative Model Learned phobia [[Little Albert Study]] Equipotentiality premise: assumes that all neutral stimuli have an equal potential for becoming phobias. Non-Associative Model Biological predisposition for acquiring certain phobias Failure to [[Habituation]] (lack of exposure) + genetic vulnerability to [[Anxiety]] = [[Specific Phobia]] Disgust sensitivity: the degree to which people are susceptible to being disgusted by a variety of stimuli such as certain bugs, types of food, and small animals Caused by the [[Autonomic nervous system#Sympathetic Division]] activation [[Social Anxiety Disorder]] ==Symptoms== What are the key [[Separation Anxiety Disorder#Symptoms|symptoms]] of SAD Afraid of social or performance situations High comorbidity (ex.</description></item><item><title>PSY240: - L12&amp;13&amp;14</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy240/psy240-l121314/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy240/psy240-l121314/</guid><description>Reading Describe the symptoms and clinical features of the major unipolar and bipolar mood disorders. Depressive disorders involve a change in mood to depression, and include major depressive disorder (MDD) and dysthymia. Symptoms of MDD include persistent feelings of sadness, loss of interest in activities, loss of appetite or weight loss, insomnia, low energy, feelings of worthlessness or guilt, difficulty concentrating or making decisions, and suicidality. At least five of these symptoms must be present for at least two weeks, although episodes of MDD typically last for several months.</description></item><item><title>PSY240: - L15</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy240/psy240-l15/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy240/psy240-l15/</guid><description>Reading Explain why schizophrenia is viewed as one of the most serious, disabling, and complex mental disorders Schizophrenia is a psychotic disorder that may affect both men and women in late adolescence and early adulthood. The disorder is complex and heterogeneous in its clinical presentation, course, and outcome. Approximately 50 percent of patients with schizophrenia improve over time and in response to treatment, but few achieve their social and occupational potential, and many require lifelong support and remain at risk for suicide.</description></item><item><title>PSY240: - L16</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy240/psy240-l16/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy240/psy240-l16/</guid><description>Lecture What is the most important issue with diagnostic with [[Schizophrenia]]? Subjectivity: Relies on a person&amp;rsquo;s presenting symptoms Reliable diagnostic ≠ Valid diagnostic Strategies to improve? Endophenotypes: biological or behavioural predispositions that makes a disorder more likely Examples Processing Speed: slowness writing symbols paired with numbers ($71-75%$) Sensory Gating: Impaired ability to filter out redundant information ($63-80%$) Verbal Memory: Impaired learning and recall of words and stories ($62-75%$) Dichotic Listening: Impaired ability to attend to one message and ignore another ($50-71%$) Phnemic Word Fluency: Reduced ability to generate words rapidly ($53-64%$) Continuous Performance Test: Slow and inaccurate detection of specified letters ($52-62%$) ==Etiology== Theories related to [[Schizophrenia]] Psycho-social models [[Carl Jung]]: collective unconscious (similar delusion contexts) Social Drift: explain the connection of schizophrenia with poverty rates Meehl&amp;rsquo;s Theory Schizogene -&amp;gt; cognitive slippage -&amp;gt; aversive drift -&amp;gt; schizotype [[Diathesis Stress Model]] Inherited/fetal injury -&amp;gt; &amp;ldquo;switches&amp;rdquo; in the brain turned on by stress Biological vulnerability inherited or acquired early in life Biological factors Genetic contribution Fraternal twins &amp;amp; first degree relative $6-17%$ Identical twins: $48%$ Exposure to flu in utero [[Brain]] related Reduced grey matter volume (slower processing) Activation of left temporal lobe: hallucination\ Amygdala &amp;amp; hippocampus [[Dopamine]] Hypothesis Dopamine dysregulation promote psychotic symptoms Blocking dopamine receptors are effective in treating schizophrenia ==Treatment== for schizophrenia Antipsychotic medication Promethazzine (anti nausea) Chlorpromazine (used for mood disorders mania agitation) 1st generation Lots of side effects (motor dysfunctions, weight gain) Risperidone &amp;amp; Olanzapine (symtom control with fewer side effects) Ativan: anti-anxiety medication Psychotherapy Emotional disturbance Psychotic symptoms Social Disabilities Risk of relapse Cognitive Promote independence Stresses reduction Function disability control Family therapy Involvement of family Sense of family members Deinstitutionalization</description></item><item><title>PSY240: - L17&amp;18</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy240/psy240-l1718/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy240/psy240-l1718/</guid><description>Lecture What is the difference between personality, treats, and personality disorders Personality: consistent behaviour and thinking characteristics of a person Trait: characteristic features of a person that displayed persistency [[Personality Disorders]]: maladaptive, inflexible, and restricted ways of behaving, feeling, and thinking (sigle dominant trait) What is the difference between egosyntonic and egodystonic Egosyntonic: behaviors, values, and feelings that are in harmony with or acceptable to the needs and goals of the ego Egodystonic: behaviors, values, and feelings that are not in harmony with or acceptable to the needs and goals of the ego Prevalence $6-9%$ of the population Diagnostic for adults psychological autopsies A set of interviews to determine whether a person was suffering from personality disorder after suicide ==Diagnostic== Criteria for [[Personality Disorders#Cluster A]] [[Paranoid Personality Disorder]] $&amp;gt;4/7$: Pervasive suspiciousness, non-bizarre [[Paranoid Personality Disorder#Diagnosis|symptoms]] Differential diagnosis with [[Schizophrenia]] Reality testing, paranoid people would look for actual evidence, schizophrenia will not with their delusions [[Schizoid Personality Disorder]] $&amp;gt;4/7$: Lack of emotional responsiveness, loners [[Schizoid Personality Disorder#Diagnosis|symptoms]] [[Schizotypal Personality Disorder]] $&amp;gt;5/9$: Eccentricity, socially isolated [[Schizotypal Personality Disorder#Diagnosis|symptoms]] Differential diagnosis with [[Schizophrenia]] Don&amp;rsquo;t have hallucinations and delusions (reality testing) Cooccur with [[Mood Disorder]] ==Diagnostic== Criteria for [[Personality Disorders#Cluster B]] [[Antisocial Personality Disorder]] $&amp;gt;3/7$ Disregard for, and violation of, the rights of others [[Antisocial Personality Disorder#Diagnosis|symptoms]] Differential diagnostics Narcissistic: exploitive and uncompassionate, but not aggressive or deceitful [[Borderline Personality Disorder|BPD]]: manipulative, but reassurance and nurture Substance use: must be ruled out ==Etiology== for [[Antisocial Personality Disorder]] Family: disruptive Genetics: heritability $44-72%$ Fearlessness hypothesis A higher threshold for feeling fear than do other people Indifferent to punishment, or oppositional to others’ attempts to control them Based on early learning experiences What is the difference between psychopathy and [[Antisocial Personality Disorder|ASPD]] ASPD: diagnosis based on behavioural features Psychopathy: a richer set of emotional, interpersonal, and behavioural features Psychopathy and aggression: strong link Prevalence: $1%$ of population ==Etiology== [[Amygdala]] Serotonergic hypofunctioning in combination with a high dopamine activity Fundamental psychopathy vs.</description></item><item><title>PSY240: - L19</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy240/psy240-l19/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy240/psy240-l19/</guid><description>Lecture Define the below vocabularies Addition: substance use disorder Polysubstance abuse disorder: The simultaneous misuse or dependence upon two or more substances Synergistic -&amp;gt; dangerous What are some diagnostic imdicators Impairment of control Social impairment Risky use Pharmacological dependence</description></item><item><title>PSY240: - L2</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy240/psy240-l2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy240/psy240-l2/</guid><description>Reading Describe why we need a classification system for mental disorders. A diagnostic system for mental disorders serves a number of important functions, such as providing a description of mental disorders, distinguishing among different types of mental disorders, providing a vocabulary for communicating about mental disorders, and facilitating research in psychopathology. Furthermore, accurate assessment and diagnosis, as well as effective treatment of mental disorders, rely on a system of classification.</description></item><item><title>PSY240: - L3</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy240/psy240-l3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy240/psy240-l3/</guid><description>Reading Questions View behaviour and thinking (disordered or not) as arising from the interaction between biological and environmental experiences. There has been a consistent move toward viewing the etiology of mental health problems from an integrative perspective. Biological, psychological, and socio-cultural factors interact in complex ways to produce psychiatric disorders. Single-factor theories are unlikely to explain the etiology of any disorder, and are gradually falling into disuse. Theories gain strength not because the evidence supports their predictions but rather because alternative explanations are rejected.</description></item><item><title>PSY240: - L4</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy240/psy240-l4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy240/psy240-l4/</guid><description>Reading Questions Explain how classical and operant conditioning can influence an individual’s behaviour and provide examples. Behavioural theorists argue that all or almost all human behaviour, including abnormal behaviour, is learned. In classical conditioning, a neutral stimulus (the CS) comes to elicit a conditioned response (CR) through its being paired with another stimulus (UCS) that already elicits that reflexive response (UCR). In operant conditioning, when a behaviour increases in frequency in response to consistent consequences, reinforcement is said to occur; when the behaviour decreases in frequency as a result of its consequences, this is described as punishment.</description></item><item><title>PSY240: - L5</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy240/psy240-l5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy240/psy240-l5/</guid><description>Reading Differentiate between psychological testing and psychological assessment and describe the importance of this distinction Psychological testing involves gathering a sample of behaviour to determine a set of scores on a given measure. Psychometrically strong (i.e., reliable and valid) psychological tests contribute to a well-rounded psychological assessment. Psychological assessment plays an important role in abnormal psychology, providing a comprehensive system for describing an individual’s psychological profile. A psychological test provides a piece of information that must be integrated and evaluated within the context of other information to create a thorough psychological assessment Explain the importance of reliability and validity in clinical assessment.</description></item><item><title>PSY240: - L6</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy240/psy240-l6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy240/psy240-l6/</guid><description>Reading Explain the challenges of assessing the abilities of individuals with intellectual/developmental disorders People with developmental disabilities may be given lower priority for services than others or excluded from medical and surgical interventions Damage is manifested in a number of ways depending on the condition, including unusual physical features; particular types of cognitive, language, motor, or other deficits; and patterns of behaviour (e.g., hyperactivity, stereotypy, aggressiveness). Identify different ways that intellectual disabilities might be caused Neurodevelopment disorders are associated with varying degrees of damage to the brain occurring at different stages of development before, during, or after birth The etiology of neurodevelopmental disorders in general and intellectual disability in particular is complex.</description></item><item><title>PSY240: - L7</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy240/psy240-l7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy240/psy240-l7/</guid><description>Reading Identify variables that need to be measured when evaluating community integration and inclusion. Explain varying prevalence rates for autism spectrum disorders The deinstitutionalization and mainstreaming movements have emphasized the importance of community integration. However they have also highlighted the potential risks of vulnerability and exploitation in community inclusion. Evaluation of community-based care and quality of life has become an important area of work for psychologists Systematic intensive early intervention programs applying operant conditioning principles have been found effective in developing language and social skills and in managing challenging behaviour.</description></item><item><title>PSY240: - L8</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy240/psy240-l8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy240/psy240-l8/</guid><description>Reading Identify the current issues associated with assessing and treating children and adolescents with mental health problems. Issues with assessing The opinion of the child’s difficulties can differ by the informant. Teachers have been shown to be better respondents than parents about severity of ADHD and social functioning. Parents have been shown to be the most comprehensive respondents about disruptive behaviour, although they under-report conduct symptoms compared to the child.</description></item><item><title>PSY240: - L9</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy240/psy240-l9/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy240/psy240-l9/</guid><description>Lecture PDF: [[Class9.pdf]] Prevalence of Childhood Disorders About $20%$ of youth have a psychological disorder ADHD, CD, Anxiety Disorders What are some issues with assessing and Treating Children Parents’ and teachers’ reports are often considered more important in assessment than the child’s input. Examine the role that the environment plays in children’s symptoms Some childhood problems persist or become worse into adulthood Homotypic continuity: predictive of future same diagnostic Heterotypic continuity: predictive of future different diagnosis Anxiety to depression; ADHD to ODD Externalizing: Oppositional Defiant Disorder &amp;amp; [[Conduct Disorder]] ==Diagnostic==: What are the 3 diagnostic categories of ODD (A) .</description></item><item><title>PSY260: - L1</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy260/psy260-l1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy260/psy260-l1/</guid><description>Keypoints Clive Wearing Wearing&amp;rsquo;s dual retrograde-anterograde amnesia ([[Anterograde Amnesia]]) phenomenon is often referred to as &amp;lsquo;30-second Clive&amp;rsquo; in reference to his 30-second episodic memory capacity Damage of hippocampus Procedure memories are not damaged Jimmie G. Neurological impairment known as Korsakov&amp;rsquo;s syndrome, a condition caused by alcohol-related damage to the mammillary bodies in the brain. Korsakov&amp;rsquo;s syndrome impairs short-term memory and causes retrograde amnesia—the inability to recall memories.</description></item><item><title>PSY260: - L10</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy260/psy260-l10/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy260/psy260-l10/</guid><description>Reading In operant conditioning, () signal whether a particular response will lead to a particular outcome.1 () refers to actions or behaviors that benefit another individual at the expense of some cost to the actor. Some such actions may reflect (), or “tit-for-tat” behavior, in which one friend helps another with the expectation that the friend will reciprocate later on.2 The () is a part of the brain that helps determine subjective values of punishers, such as whether the intense heat of a chili pepper on the tongue is perceived as pleasurable or painful.</description></item><item><title>PSY260: - L13</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy260/psy260-l13/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy260/psy260-l13/</guid><description>Reading The general term for conditions involving severe memory loss is (). More specifically, loss of the ability to form new declarative memories is called (), while the loss of previously acquired information is called ().1 Three ways in which memory can be tested are free recall, which entails (); cued recall, which entails (); and recognition, which entails (). Of the three, () usually produces the best performance.2 The “() effect” refers to the phenomenon that memory is usually best when the cues available at testing are similar to those at encoding; the “() effect” refers to the phenomenon that memory is usually best when information is processed in the same way at encoding and retrieval.</description></item><item><title>PSY260: - L14</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy260/psy260-l14/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy260/psy260-l14/</guid><description>Lecture PDF: [[Memory Processes]]: Encoding, Consolidation and Retrieval What (2) strategies are effective and not effective for memory encoding? Effective: Relation [[law of Association|association]] to prior knowledge Understanding of the concept (depth of processing) Low-level processing is harder to encode High-level processing is easier to encode Not effective: simple repetition What does hippocampus play in memory consolidation? [[Memory Processes#^c45b78|Systematic Consolidation]] How can [[Electroconvulsive therapy|ECT]] effect reconsolidation?</description></item><item><title>PSY260: - L15</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy260/psy260-l15/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy260/psy260-l15/</guid><description>Textbook Surfing is an example of a(n) () skill because surfers have to adapt to variations in the qualities of each wave.1 Updating a website is an example of a(n) () skill because it requires using computer programming knowledge to solve a problem.2 Skiing is an example of a(n) () skill because it requires coordinating movements based on sensory information.3 Historically, researchers have questioned whether it is possible for animals other than humans to learn () skills.</description></item><item><title>PSY260: - L16</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy260/psy260-l16/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy260/psy260-l16/</guid><description>Reading Lecture Expertise What is the [[Pual Fitts|Fitts]]&amp;rsquo;s three-stage model of skills (motor programs)? Motor programs: sequences of movements performed virtually automatically [[Skilled Memory#Three-stage Model of Skill Learning]] What is an expert? An expert is someone who has mastered a skill better than most people What type of learning that experts that differs than average? Perceptual learning How does one become an expert Through extensive [[Practice]] Some estimates indicate a minimum of $10,000$ hours of practice is required for deep expertise in a complex skill Some psychologists maintain that practice alone is sufficient to become an expert in any domain (though perhaps not worldclass) Through talent (the ability to master a skill with little effort) Studies of twins confirm that both talent and effort matter Brain Substrates [[Basal Ganglia]] Where is basal ganglia located?</description></item><item><title>PSY260: - L17&amp;L18</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy260/psy260-l17l18/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy260/psy260-l17l18/</guid><description>Textbooks In the Tower of Hanoi puzzle, moving all the disks to the right is an abstract plan that depends on the () part of the frontal lobes, whereas specific plans for completing individual steps to solve the puzzle (e.g., moving the yellow disk to the middle peg) depend on a more () part of the frontal lobes.1 In the Wisconsin Card Sorting Test, frequently used in clinical settings, patients with frontal-lobe lesions show (); that is, they fail to learn a new rule despite feedback indicating that the old rule is incorrect.</description></item><item><title>PSY260: - L19</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy260/psy260-l19/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy260/psy260-l19/</guid><description>Reading Emotion involves three distinct but interrelated phenomena namely (), (), (), and that are produced in response to an affecting situation.1 The () theory of emotion states that conscious feelings of emotion occur after the mind senses the physiological responses associated with arousal. The () theory of emotion states that conscious feelings of emotion and bodily responses (physiological responses and overt behaviors) occur simultaneously and independently. The () theory of emotion states that a combination of cognitive appraisal and perception of biological changes together determine our experience of emotion.</description></item><item><title>PSY260: - L2</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy260/psy260-l2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy260/psy260-l2/</guid><description>Reading TB Questions According to Aristotle’s principle of 1, we form a strong association between peanut butter and jelly because they appear together very often. Plato was a proponent of (), which holds that the bulk of our knowledge is ingrained from birth. His student Aristotle was identified with a school of thought known as (), which claims that our ideas stem from experience. 2 The belief that the mind and body exist as separate entities is known as ().</description></item><item><title>PSY260: - L20</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy260/psy260-l20/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy260/psy260-l20/</guid><description>Lecture Infancy through childhood Can children learn before birth? How? Auditory [[Habituation]] for baby in womb What kind of [[Memory]] do infants have? Infants have [[Semantic Memory]]: elicited imitation [[Episodic Memory]] seems to develop more slowly What is the language learning sensitive/critical period? Before 12 years of age, after lose the ability to master due to phonetic discriminations What is the difference between children language learning and adult language learning Children: learn and categories from exposure, gradually categories exposed inputs Adult: apply predisposed categories based on previous experience Adolescent, adulthood, old age What is the developmental feature for adolescence?</description></item><item><title>PSY260: - L3</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy260/psy260-l3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy260/psy260-l3/</guid><description>Reading Questions The brain and spinal cord together make up the ()1 Sensory receptors in your fingers and toes are part of your ().2 The temporal lobe, parietal lobe, occipital lobe, and frontal lobe are all subdivisions of the ().3 The () looks like a smaller brain hiding underneath the cerebral cortex and helps coordinate sensation and movement.4 () collect neurotransmitters released from a presynaptic neuron.5 Varieties of cells such as astrocytes and oligodendrocytes that are found throughout the brain are collectively called ()6 A major technique currently used to collect structural images of human brains is ().</description></item><item><title>PSY260: - L4</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy260/psy260-l4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy260/psy260-l4/</guid><description>Reading Questions Equipotentiality Versus Phrenology What are the main differences between the explanations of brain function proposed by Franz Joseph Gall and those ultimately proposed by Karl Lashley? What evidence did each use to support his viewpoint? Lecture PDF ![[260 L4 Slide.pdf]] Summary Functional Properties of Learning and Memory Systems What Brains Do [[Peripheral Nervous System|PNS]] -&amp;gt; [[Spine]] -&amp;gt; [[Brain]] --&amp;gt; [[Peripheral Nervous System|PNS]] Sensory signals (produced by stimuli) are initially processed in [[Brain#Diencephalon|cortical regions]] specialized for processing such signals, and they ultimately lead to activity in other cortical regions, such as the motor cortex, that are specialized for coordinating movements (responses).</description></item><item><title>PSY260: - L5&amp;L6</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy260/psy260-l5l6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy260/psy260-l5l6/</guid><description>Reading If you are nervous about driving in the rain because you once slid off the road when it was raining, you may have become () to driving in the rain.1 If you don’t mind getting fillings at the dentist because you’ve had so much dental work in the past, you probably are () to dental drills.2 If you’ve become habituated to the beeping of a fire alarm with a low battery near your bedroom, then having a crow attack you in your bedroom may () your responses to the beeping.</description></item><item><title>PSY260: - L8</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy260/psy260-l8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy260/psy260-l8/</guid><description>Lecture PDF: ![[260 L8 Slide.pdf]] What is the Basic paradigms of Classical Conditioning? What are the 4 basic concept of [[Classical Conditioning]]? ![[Classical Conditioning#^368756]] What is the difference between appetitive and aversive conditioning? Appetitive conditioning: consists of learning to predict something that satisfies a desire or an appetite Food and sex are among the most powerful of appetitive USs Aversive conditioning: new CS -&amp;gt; CR reflex helps avoid noxious US Conditioning in which the US is a disagreeable event Many of the procedures used for the experimental study of conditioning are aversive conditioning Unconditioned stimulus, US Unconditioned response UR Conditioned stimulus, CS Conditioned response, CR Appetitive conditioning Pavlov&amp;rsquo;s dog Food Salivation Bell Salivation Quail sex Sexually available female Approach, mounting, and copulation Light Approach Aversive conditioning Conditioned emotional response (Fear conditioning) Shock Freezing Jumping and running around for a few seconds Tone Freezing Eyeblink conditioning Airpuff Blink Tone Blink [[Eyeblink Condiitoning]] ^47d0bb A form of aversive conditioning: CS -&amp;gt; CR prepares to avoid US Puff of air to eye (US) innately produces eyeblink (UR) CS: a tone or light, comes to produce a gradual eye closure (CR) Initially the CS (tone) causes no response The effectiveness of the CS builds gradually over many pairings with the US The CR is not exactly the same as the UR: it takes place before the US and can even be different in speed, form, etc Works on rabbits and humans, but takes many trials What is a Conditioned Compensatory Responses Conditioned Compensatory Response: a CR that is the opposite of the UR, helping to balance/correct for the US-UR reflex Tolerance: A decrease in reaction to a drug such that larger doses are required to achieve the same effect Inject adrenaline (US) -&amp;gt; heart rate increase (UR) Repeat procedure in same testing chamber (CS) Eventually, CS comes to produce a decrease in heart rate (CR) that helps maintain homeostasis (balance) against expected adrenaline injection What is Extinction and how it works Extinction: the process of reducing a learned response to a stimulus by ceasing to pair that stimulus with another, previously associated stimulus Extinction probably doesn’t erase the CS-US connection, just inhibits it Present the CS alone repeatedly Initially, CS evokes strong CRs With repetition, however, CS becomes less effective, similar to beginning of training What are the 4 rules of interest in [[Classical Conditioning]]?</description></item><item><title>PSY260: - L9</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy260/psy260-l9/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy260/psy260-l9/</guid><description>Reading The relationship between a US and a UR does/does not involve learning1 In eyeblink conditioning, the blink is both a(n) () and a(n) () , although they differ in their ().2 In most conditioning paradigms, extinction is faster/slower than the original acquisition of the conditioned response.3 [?] 4. () conditioned responses in the body are most often the result of a biological mechanism called ()4 Evidence that extinction is more than just unlearning comes primarily from studies that look at shifts in () between learning and testing.</description></item><item><title>PSY322 Reading 1</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy322/psy322-reading-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy322/psy322-reading-1/</guid><description>Topics DUE [[2023-01-25]] WEIGHT: $10%$ Contents Instructions: Pay attention to any figures or graphs in the articles, even if they are not directly referred to below. Make sure you can identify the major elements of the figure and explain them. These guides are intended to help you with studying the readings and preparing for the Quiz. Most Quiz questions about these readings will relate to the topics below, but there may be questions on the Quiz not directly addressed below, so be sure that you have read the whole article.</description></item><item><title>PSY322 Reading 4</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy322/psy322-reading-4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy322/psy322-reading-4/</guid><description>Topics DUE [[2023-03-15]] Readings [@2019BOGART-BornThatWay] What is the authors’ central idea? What is the new contribution to science of this set of studies? Central idea Congenital disabilities are often stigmatized as being helpless and dependent Acquired disabilities are viewed as being capable of living a &amp;ldquo;normal&amp;rdquo; life before their disability Different types of stigma for individuals with disabilities, including their self-perception, social relationships, and access to resources and support Contribution Congenital disability was more stigmatized than the acquired version of the same disability (Studies 1–2) People with congenital disability were more essentialized, but less blamed than people with acquired disability (Study 2) Manipulating onset and essentialism revealed that when disability was acquired, low essentialism predicted greater stigma through blame (Study 3) What is essentialism?</description></item><item><title>PSY322 Reading 5</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy322/psy322-reading-5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy322/psy322-reading-5/</guid><description>Topics DUE [[2023-03-29]] Readings ★ [@2010DIXON-LetThemEat] ^ae084a How does contact affect advantaged and disadvantaged groups? (What are similarities and differences in these effects?) Similarities Positive contact can lead to reduced prejudice and improved attitudes towards the disadvantaged group. Direct contact, such as face-to-face interaction, is generally more effective than indirect contact, such as exposure to media representations of the disadvantaged group. The effectiveness of contact in reducing prejudice is influenced by the quality and frequency of the contact.</description></item><item><title>PSY322: - L1</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy322/psy322-l1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy322/psy322-l1/</guid><description>Lecture PDF: [[322 - S1.pdf]] A scientific perspective [[Reliability|reliable]] and [[Validity|valid]] methods, unbiased daa, replicable What is the role of values, of how we think the world should be? Values do not affect how we evaluate validity of results Values can affect the questions we ask Values can affect what we do with scientific knowledge Definitions [[Stereotype]]: a (cognitive) belief about a specific group Thinking about exceptions indicate a existing stereotype [[Prejudice]]: (emotional) feelings about a specific group [[Discrimination]]: (behaviour) act toward a specific group Research on mindsets What are the two different mindsets, and how they differ?</description></item><item><title>PSY322: - L10</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy322/psy322-l10/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy322/psy322-l10/</guid><description>Lecture PDF: [[322 - S10.pdf]] Identifying prejudice in organization ^b54327 What is the diversity structure in company? Evidence of promoting representation, treatment, and inclusion of underrepresented groups Ex. Organizational mission statements, diversity trainings, diversity awards How can procedurally fair differ from actual fairness? ^7e139f [Kaiser et al, 2013] Rationalization Indicate that the company have intensions to promote diversity (credit for effort) Diversity structures may be seen as an indicator of diversity effort efficacy, even if they don’t actually achieve equity Diversity structures may be a function of legal strategy to inoculate a company against discrimination claims Costs (financial &amp;amp; social) may be greater in claiming discrimination at a company that touts itself as promoting diversity What are some important benefits and limits of diversity structures Benefits Changing norms Raise awareness of biases Trust among underrepresented groups Limitations Study of 30 years’ data, 700 organizations Outcome measure: change in % Black and White managers Most diversity structures unrelated to actual diversity within the organization Diversity trainings on reducing manager bias: associated with subsequent decreases in racial diversity Assigning people to do things they don&amp;rsquo;t believe (no internal motivation), might elicit back fire effect (forced external pressure) Bringing attention to racial identity might leading to aversive racism (hyper vigilance/salient of bias) Punishment oriented Prejudice reduction What are some common ways to reduce prejudice Changing norms Common ingroup identity Diversity structures ^ed9dfe Sidelining bias Ingroup contact Sidelining bias ^c483bf [Okonofua et al, 2022] Feature Popular approach: reducing bias Situationist approach: sidelining bias Goal To change the person, by training bias out of the person To activate an alternative working self with ideal goals that are endorsed by the person and for which bias would be not functional, thereby reducing the impact of bias on behavior Focus Individual differences Contextual differences Emphasis on bias Primary and explicit Secondary or absent How people are treated As problematic, with deficits As good, with strengths that can be used for working toward ideal goals Primary outcomes Measures of bias in the person Real-life consequences of bias of inherent importance Sidelining bias vs.</description></item><item><title>PSY322: - L2</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy322/psy322-l2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy322/psy322-l2/</guid><description>Lecture PDF: [[322 - S2.pdf]] Psychology methods What are the 6 stages of [[Scientific Method]]? Why use the scientific method Intuition &amp;amp; common sense can be faulty [[Milgram Experiment]]: obedience to authority Bystander effect Biased interpretation of evidence Naive realism: people think they perceive the world as &amp;ldquo;objective&amp;rdquo; Human are not aware of their own bias Bias blindspot Basic definitions What is the difference between stereotype, prejudice, and discrimination?</description></item><item><title>PSY322: - L3</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy322/psy322-l3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy322/psy322-l3/</guid><description>Lecture [[322 Quiz 1]]
PDF: [[322 - S3.pdf]] [[Social categorization]] and [[Social Identity]] What is social categorization and the most apparent features for categorization? Social categorization: tendency to categorize automatically with minimal info Social identity: born out of social categorization Human detect race, sex, and age within milliseconds What are some similarities between them What are some importance of categorization? ★ Precursor to [[Stereotype]] and [[Prejudice]] Perspective 1 on social bias: [[Realistic Conflict Theory]]?</description></item><item><title>PSY322: - L5</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy322/psy322-l5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy322/psy322-l5/</guid><description>Lecture PDF: [[322 - S5.pdf]] Threat-Based Approach What does negative [[Prejudice]] mean? Negative feelings toward all sorts of social groups based on ethnicity, immigration status, gender or sexual minority, etc What are the recurrent adaptive problems of social life? Functional evolutionary approach Left-over effect Stereotyping and prejudice may be psychological mechanisms designed to help humans address these recurrent adaptive challenges (disease, health, physical danger, safety, reciprocity) Error management Smoke Detector Principle Motivated to see people as threatening even if they are not Threat as perceived threat rather than actual threat Overly sensitive &amp;gt; Under sensitive: assume harmless is dangerous OR Assume dangerous as harmless Behavioural immune system Avoid contact with people who may be sick; overly inclusive Emotional evoked for threatening to health is predominately disgust Sensitive to cues of illness Call back to [[Affordance management]] People perceive groups to pose different threats and positive opportunities Stereotypes of specific threats (belief) --&amp;gt; specific prejudice (emotions) Fear, disgust, anger tend to be common emotion, leads to different behaviour Physical danger --&amp;gt; fear --&amp;gt; violence, aggression Disease, value difference --&amp;gt; disgust --&amp;gt; Goal obstruction --&amp;gt; anger --&amp;gt; Implications Who are more likely to contain prejudice?</description></item><item><title>PSY322: - L6</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy322/psy322-l6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy322/psy322-l6/</guid><description>Lecture PDF: [[322 - S6.pdf]] [[2015 - The Effects of Sexualized Female Characters in Superhero Films on Women]] Group Norm Theory ^85b107 What are the 2 problems in traditional prejudice study? Studying one prejudice at a time To really understand prejudice, should look at prejudice toward many group Decrease in expressed prejudice: read or just conforming to norms? There are multiple explanations for decrease expression in prejudice: change in attitude or internalization of prevailing social norm OR conformity without internalization Charlesworth &amp;amp; Banaji (2019) [[Out-Group#Implicit Association Test]] What new perspective did group norm theory propose?</description></item><item><title>PSY322: - L7</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy322/psy322-l7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy322/psy322-l7/</guid><description>Lecture PDF: [[322 - S7.pdf]] [[322 - L6#^85b107|Group Norm Theory]] ^73ac49 [[322 - L6#^a649ef|Prejudice acceptability]] Some prejudice is acceptable (Ofosu et all, 2019) Same-sex marriage legalization was published in 2015. For states that passed legalization locally Implicit bias and explicit bias both showed decrease of bias after legalization For states that did not pass legalization locally They all showed gradual decrease for prejudice toward gay people before federal legalization After legalization, they showed increase in prejudice toward gay people Reason Stronger in-group belonging within states Brought attention to this matter Change in law that is very salient to citizen caused reversal effect When we see reductions in explicit prejudice, what does that mean?</description></item><item><title>PSY322: - L8</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy322/psy322-l8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy322/psy322-l8/</guid><description>Lecture PDF: [[322 - S8.pdf]] Changing in implicit bias What are the 2 most effective way to improve implicit bias: Train one&amp;rsquo;s mind to form association set of concepts (the core of IAT) Invoke one&amp;rsquo;s motivation (explicit or implicit) to change biases What is the least successful ways to change bias When people are induced with threat, will evoke biases Self affirmation (reinforce self image) Specific moods/emotions would not change biases much What are the 3 puzzles about implicit bias and ways to resolve it Replicable implicit bias on average for a group, and constantly shifting individual scores IAT might be helpful for indicating a group/culture context, but less useful for assessing individual differences The individual differences cancels out/washed out in large group statistics Same effects across ages If one’s biases are not stable across a month, how can they be stable across a lifetime?</description></item><item><title>PSY322: - L9</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy322/psy322-l9/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy322/psy322-l9/</guid><description>Lecture PDF: [[322 - S9.pdf]] [[Social Self#Self Esteem]] Identifying bias in ourselves Self-enhancement such as the bias blindspot (e.g., “others are definitely biased, but I’m not) Pronin et al (2002) ^b255e4 [[Better Than Average Effect]] [[322 - L7#^9aa9da|Aversive racism]] Moral Credentials Many people seek to maintain a non-prejudice;d self image When they have recently had an opportunity to act non-prejudiced, concern is temporarily lifted Acting non-prejudiced = “moral credentials” Implication: Does this idea mean people may be more likely to act prejudiced if they perceive themselves to have enough moral credentials?</description></item><item><title>PSY424: - L1</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy424/psy424-l1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy424/psy424-l1/</guid><description>Reading The Nature and Importance of Intimacy The Nature of Intimacy: Intimate relationships differ from more casual associations in at least seven specific ways: knowledge, interdependence, caring, trust, responsiveness, mutuality, and commitment. The Need to Belong: Humans display a need to belong, a drive to maintain regular interaction with affectionate, intimate partners. Adverse consequences may follow if the need remains unfulfilled over time. The Influence of Culture: Fewer people are marrying than ever before, and those who do marry wait longer to do so.</description></item><item><title>PSY424: - L11</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy424/psy424-l11/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy424/psy424-l11/</guid><description>Lecture PDF: [[424 - S11.pdf]] Relationship maintenance What are the cognitive maintenance mechanisms Cognitive interdependence Mutuality &amp;amp; change in self-definition [[Intimate Relationship#Mutuality]] Inclusion of other in the self Resources, traits, perspectives Changes in self-concept Postive illusions Idealization of partner (friendship, marital relationships) People with illusions with their partner tend to have better relationships Increases own satisfaction, partner’s satisfaction and relationship commitment Aware of faults but Relationship enhancing attributions (attribute to external factors) Misremember them Global level (view their partner in general) vs.</description></item><item><title>PSY424: - L2</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy424/psy424-l2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy424/psy424-l2/</guid><description>Reading Chapter 3 Basis of [[Attraction]]: We are attracted to people whose presence is rewarding because they offer us instrumentality, assistance in achieving our goals.
Proximity: Liking Those Near Us We select our friends, and our enemies, from those around us. Familiarity: Repeated Contact: In general, familiarity breeds attraction. Even brief, mere exposure to others usually increases our liking for them. Convenience: Proximity Is Rewarding, Distance Is Costly: Relationships with distant partners are ordinarily less satisfying than they would be if the partners were nearby.</description></item><item><title>PSY424: - L3</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy424/psy424-l3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy424/psy424-l3/</guid><description>Reading Interdependency: which exists when we need others and they need us in order to obtain valuable interpersonal rewards.
Social Exchange [[Interdependence theory]] offers an economic view of relationships that involves social exchange in which partners provide each other desirable rewards. Rewards and Costs: Rewards are gratifying and costs are punishing. The net profit or loss from an interaction is its outcome. What Do We Expect from Our Relationships: People have comparison levels $CLs$ that reflect their expectations for their interactions with others.</description></item><item><title>PSY424: - L4</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy424/psy424-l4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy424/psy424-l4/</guid><description>Reading [[Nonverbal Communication]] Nonverbal communication serves vital functions, providing information, regulating interaction, and defining the nature of the relationship two people share. Components of Nonverbal Communication. Facial expression: Facial expressions are good guides to others’ moods, but cultural norms influence expressive behavior. Gazing behavior: The direction and amount of a person’s looking is important in defining relationships and in regulating interaction. In addition, our pupils dilate when we’re seeing something that interests us.</description></item><item><title>PSY424: - L5</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy424/psy424-l5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy424/psy424-l5/</guid><description>Lecture Families are complex systems composed of interconnected subsystems that mutually influence each other
Families are affected by a number of transitions, each of which can influence family structure, processes or both
PDF: [[424 - S5.pdf]] [[Family]] as theories [[Family#^b873ea|Sullivan Interpersonal Theory]] Provide with first model with interpersonal interactions [[Attachment]] Crucial in how one view themselves and expectation of how to interact with others Contribute to adult relationships [[Psychoanalysis]] Important for personality development ([[Psychoanalysis#Psychosexual Stage Model|psychosexual stages]]) Especially important for the first 6 years of life (oral, annal, phallic) [[Alfred Alder]] Parenting in early in life influences feelings of inferiority (contribute to how one strive for superiority) Birth order effects personality [[Theory of Development]] Have fixed psychosocial stages Internal drive vs.</description></item><item><title>PSY424: - L6</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy424/psy424-l6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy424/psy424-l6/</guid><description>Lecture PDF: [[424 - S6.pdf]] Key factors Affective Communal Respect Mutuality Caring/affection Responsiveness Knowledge Capitalization Appreciation Identity Validation Trust Social support (Feeney &amp;amp; Collin, 2015) ==Model of Social Support== Two conditions for friendship development Times of adversity --&amp;gt; buffer against negative effects (Source of Strength and Support: SOS) Ex.</description></item><item><title>PSY424: - L7</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy424/psy424-l7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy424/psy424-l7/</guid><description>Lecture PDF: [[424 - S7.pdf]] Western history of [[Romantic Relationship|love]] What are the 7 common attributes of love PPPDJIC Preoccupation Thinking a lot about the partner &amp;amp; having little control over when these thoughts occur Proximity Taking steps to maintain or restore physical closeness or emotional contact with the partner Prioritizing Giving the relationship more importance than other interest &amp;amp; responsibilities Desire Wanting to be united with the partner, physically &amp;amp; emotionally [[Why We Love]] Joy Experiencing very strong, extensive positive emotions Idealization Believing the partner is unique &amp;amp; special Caring Experiencing &amp;amp; expression feelings of empathy and compassion for the partner What are some different orientations (attitude dimensions) toward love Cultural value Desirable or undesirable state Sexuality Sexual or nonsexual p Sexual orientation Heterosexual or homosexual Martial status Spouses only or reserved for others What are some important stages in the history of love &amp;amp; marriage Love being a prerequisite for marriage is new N.</description></item><item><title>PSY424: - L8</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy424/psy424-l8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy424/psy424-l8/</guid><description>Lecture Sexual Response Objective: physical resposne Subjective: emotional &amp;amp; cognitive response Desire --&amp;gt; Excitement --&amp;gt; Plateau --&amp;gt; Orgasm --&amp;gt; Resolution Sexual Desire Testosterone doesn’t predict sex drive beyond minimum threshold (men and for women pre-menopause) Sexual orientation: definition An enduring pattern of cognitive, motivational, and behavioural tendencies that regulates the experience, conduct, and expression of sexuality Dimension for Sexual Orientation Romantic attraction: 纯爱战士, love and emotion Sexual arousal: physiological response Sexual attraction: 性幻想 Sexual behaviour: interaction Sexual identity: descriptive label and the emotional reactions Unsafe sex Underestimation of risk (underestimate of risk, illusion of invulnerability) Faulty decision making (sexual arousal, intoxication) Pluralistic Ignorance Inequalities in power Abstinence education Low self-control Decreased intimacy and pleasure Sexual Coercion ==Self-determination theory== Autonomy, Competence, Relatedness Active Studying Summarize today&amp;rsquo;s lecture [::Most important/focused topic] [::Most difficult part, why, how to resolve] What part I didn&amp;rsquo;t understand, next step actions?</description></item><item><title>PSY424: - L9</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy424/psy424-l9/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/psy424/psy424-l9/</guid><description>Lecture PDF: Conflict, Stress &amp;amp; Power ==Peterson’s General Model of Conflict==: Beginging ==[Engagement]==&amp;gt; Middel ==&amp;gt; Termiantion Beginnings: Predisposing factors – increase likelihood of conflict Conflict of interest, situational stress, emotion and mood, personality, attachment style, stage in life Instigating events: Interference with goal-directed action Criticism, illegitimate demands, rebuffs, cumulative annoyances Engagement vs. Avoidance Engagement: Issue perceived as significant but solvable Avoidance: Issue perceived as trivial or insolvable, conflict end Middle Negotiation vs.</description></item><item><title>STA130: Lecture_1</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/sta130/sta130-lecture_1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/sta130/sta130-lecture_1/</guid><description>Intro to Statistics Statistics - arts and science of learning from data. Its a way to quantify uncertainty Data Science - includes the computational aspects and acquiring, managing, and analyzing data Reasoning and computing are both important aspects in data science Statistical Thinking Always be aware of the ==assumptions== made, are they justified? Think about where the data came from Is the data a ==random sample== (representatives of all sample) ?</description></item><item><title>STA130: Lecture_2</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/sta130/sta130-lecture_2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/sta130/sta130-lecture_2/</guid><description>Variable types and distributions Variable Types Quantitative Data (numerical values)
==The differences of numbers are meaningful== (numbers are not arbitrary labels) Continuous variables - any possible value within a certain range Discrete variables - some values within a certain range Categorical Data (values represent categories)
Nominal variables - the categories don&amp;rsquo;t have a particular order Binary - only 2 mutually exclusive outcomes (a special type fo nominal variable) Ordinal variables - the categories are ordered in a particular way Variable Distribution What value does the variable take (the possible range of the values) How often does the variable takes from each range of values (possibility of the outcome) 3 key elements: shape, centre, spread Distribution of quantitative variables Histograms Height of each bar is the frequency in which variable appear in the corresponding bin</description></item><item><title>STA130: Lecture_3</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/sta130/sta130-lecture_3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/sta130/sta130-lecture_3/</guid><description>Tidy data and data wrangling &amp;ldquo;Write code for humans, write data for computers&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; Vince Buffalo July 20, 2013
Tidy - data are in a predictable and expected format (convenient for computer to use) Principles of &amp;ldquo;tidy&amp;rdquo; data Each variable must have its own column (ex. Student name) Each observation must have its own row (ex. Student&amp;rsquo;s grade on one specific HW) Each value must have its own cell (ex.</description></item><item><title>STA130: Lecture_4&amp;5</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/sta130/sta130-lecture_45/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/sta130/sta130-lecture_45/</guid><description>Hypothesis testing Wheel of Destiny Question &amp;ldquo;Back before COVID, Stella McStat has been running a small-time gambling operation on campus for several months. For a dollar each, Stella sells one red and one black ticket for each spin of a wheel (i.e., total $2), then she spins the Wheel of Destiny. The person who holds the colour where the spinner stops gets ​$1.75 (Stella keeps $0.25 per spin for running the game and providing snacks).</description></item><item><title>STA130: Lecture_6</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/sta130/sta130-lecture_6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/sta130/sta130-lecture_6/</guid><description>Estimation and random selection Over-dependence on p-values may cause invalid results in the scientific process
The choice of $\alpha$ is arbitrary, it&amp;rsquo;s better to either comment on the strength of the evidence against $H_0$ by reporting the p-value, or at least make sure to choose a $\alpha$ before calculating the p-value
2 main branches of statistical inference
Testing - hypothesis test (evaluate evidence against a particular value for parameter) Estimation - confidence interval (estimate of a parameter, gives range of plausible values of parameter) Both based on statistics (estimates of parameters from sample) and sampling distributions (estimates of them of statistics) Goals of estimation:</description></item><item><title>STA130: Lecture_7</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/sta130/sta130-lecture_7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/sta130/sta130-lecture_7/</guid><description>Linear Regression Visualizing between 2 or more variables Scatterplot - the position of each point is determined by the values of two numerical variables: one on the horizontal (x) axis, the other on the vertical (y) axis (one point for each observation) Features of the association between the two numerical variables Form - describes the pattern that the two variables follow together
Ex. Linear, non-linear, quadratic, exponential&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>STA130: Lecture_8</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/sta130/sta130-lecture_8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/sta130/sta130-lecture_8/</guid><description>Multiple L.R. and Assessing Prediction models Branches of statistical inference Testing - a hypothesis test evaluates evidence against a particular value for a parameter Hypothesis test for one proportion Randomization test to compare the values of a parameter across two groups Estimation - confidence interval estimating a parameter (gives a range of plausible values for a parameter) Bootstrap confidence interval Prediction - predict value of a variable for an observation using a statistical model based on other variables Simple linear regression (one predictor) &amp;ndash; useful when response $y$ is numerical Multiple linear regression (multiple predictors) &amp;ndash; useful when response $y$ is numerical Classification trees - [next lecture] &amp;ndash; useful when response $y$ is categorical Measuring and assessing prediction accuracy Strategy Randomly divide the sample data into &amp;ldquo;training&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;testing&amp;rdquo; datasets</description></item><item><title>STA130: Lecture_9</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/sta130/sta130-lecture_9/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/sta130/sta130-lecture_9/</guid><description>Classification (Decision) Trees Anatomy of a classification tree Decision Tree - flowchart-like diagram that shows the various outcomes from a serious of decisions. Advantage is its easy to follow and understand Root node - the starting point of the tree (first parent node), same functionality with terminal (leaf) nodes. Leaf nodes - child nodes, contain a question or criteria to be answered, the answer splits into exactly two child nodes Terminal nodes - the node containing the prediction results of the decision tree.</description></item><item><title>UofT Notes</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/uoft-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/uoft-notes/uoft-notes/</guid><description>ANT100 [[ANT100: Lecture_1]] [[ANT100: Lecture_2]] [[ANT100: Lecture_3&amp;amp;4]] [[ANT100: Lecture_5&amp;amp;6]] [[ANT100: Lecture_7]] [[ANT100: Lecture_8]] [[ANT100: Lecture_9&amp;amp;11]] [[ANT100: Lecture_12]] [[ANT100: Lecture_13]] [[ANT100: Lecture_14]] [[ANT100: Lecture_15]] [[ANT100: Lecture_16]] [[ANT100: Lecture_17]] [[ANT100: Lecture_18]] [[ANT100: Lecture_19]] [[ANT100: Lecture_20]] [[ANT100: Lecture_21]] [[ANT100: Lecture_22]] [[ANT100: Lecture_23]] [[ANT100: Lecture_24]] [[ANT100: Lecture_25]] [[ANT100: Lecture_26]] CSC111 [[CSC111: 1_Linked Lists]] [[CSC111: 2_Induction and Recursion]] [[CSC111: 3_Trees]] [[CSC111: 4_Binary Search Trees]] [[CSC111: 5_Abstract Syntax Trees]] [[CSC111: 6_Graph Class]] [[CSC111: 7_Graphs in Python]] [[CSC111: 8_Cycles and Trees]] [[CSC111: 9_Computing Spanning Tree]] [[CSC111: 10_Selection and Insertion]] [[CSC111: 11_Divide-and-Conquer]] [[CSC111: 12_Average-Case Running Time]] MAT137 [[UofT Notes/MAT137/Calculus_ Integrals.</description></item><item><title>{{title}}</title><link>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/templates/post/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mel10c.github.io/mel.zhu/templates/post/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>